<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>x86 on blog.dornea.nu</title>
    <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/x86/</link>
    <description>Recent content in x86 on blog.dornea.nu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/x86/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ringzer0 CTF - Binaries - Heap Allocator</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/11/30/ringzer0-ctf-binaries-heap-allocator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/11/30/ringzer0-ctf-binaries-heap-allocator/</guid>
      <description>First let&amp;rsquo;s collect some information about the binary itself:
$ readelf IntelligenSoftware -h ELF Header: Magic: 7f 45 4c 46 02 01 01 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 00 Class: ELF64 Data: 2&amp;#39;s complement, little endian Version: 1 (current) OS/ABI: UNIX - System V ABI Version: 0 Type: EXEC (Executable file) Machine: Advanced Micro Devices X86-64 Version: 0x1 Entry point address: 0x400688 Start of program headers: 64 (bytes into file) Start of section headers: 4608 (bytes into file) Flags: 0x0 Size of this header: 64 (bytes) Size of program headers: 56 (bytes) Number of program headers: 9 Size of section headers: 64 (bytes) Number of section headers: 30 Section header string table index: 27 Let&amp;rsquo;s see some code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ringzer0 CTF - Binaries - Time to learn x86 ASM and gdb</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/11/29/ringzer0-ctf-binaries-time-to-learn-x86-asm-and-gdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/11/29/ringzer0-ctf-binaries-time-to-learn-x86-asm-and-gdb/</guid>
      <description>This one was a quite easy one. Using radare let&amp;rsquo;s find more information about the binary:
$ r2 -AA 88eb31060c4abd0931878bf7d2dd8c1a [0x08048380]&amp;gt; iI havecode true pic false canary false nx true crypto false va true intrp /lib/ld-linux.so.2 bintype elf class ELF32 lang c arch x86 bits 32 machine Intel 80386 os linux minopsz 1 maxopsz 16 pcalign 0 subsys linux endian little stripped false static false linenum true lsyms true relocs true rpath NONE binsz 7450 Ok, now let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the entry point:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week #24</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/24/links-of-the-week-#24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/24/links-of-the-week-#24/</guid>
      <description>Suterusu Rootkit: Inline Kernel Function Hooking on x86 and ARM
  Oldboot: the first bootkit on Android
  For the Love of Money
    TCP backdoor 32764 or how we could patch the Internet (or part of it ;))   2013 Cyber Attacks Statistics (Summary)
  Decebal: Point-of-Sale Malware - 400 lines of VBScript code from Romania, Researchers warns about evolution of threats and interests to modern retailers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week #10</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/23/links-of-the-week-#10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/23/links-of-the-week-#10/</guid>
      <description> 57 startup lessons Hacking Transcend WiFi SD Cards Hacking the OS X Kernel for Fun and Profiles Here&amp;rsquo;s what you find when you scan the entire Internet in an hour noteZilla: Interactive,clickable, sheet music Linux x86 Program Start Up (How the heck do we get to main()?) Average Income per Programming Language  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week #2</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/05/24/links-of-the-week-#2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/05/24/links-of-the-week-#2/</guid>
      <description>First Glimpse into the Soul of Tamagotchi: Remember my post about 29C3? There I&amp;rsquo;ve first mentioned Natalie and her passion for Tamagotchis. She&amp;rsquo;s doing some progress! Obvisouly! I really like the screenshots. CVE-2013-2094: This is definitely the bug of the week! Have a closer detailed look here. The exploit was ported to x86. Interview with a BlackHat: Part 1, Part 2, Part 3 Your login form posts to HTTPS, but you blew it when you loaded it over HTTP: I can&amp;rsquo;t believe this is still a issue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
