<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>viz on blog.dornea.nu</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/viz/</link><description>Recent content in viz on blog.dornea.nu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/viz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Organizing and visualizing knowledge</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/09/17/organizing-and-visualizing-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/09/17/organizing-and-visualizing-knowledge/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been recently looking for some new ways organizing my notes/thoughts/tasks/bookmarks/whatever in order to keep things clean and backup valuable information. After spending some time reading others efforts to do that, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that mine were not that bad. Let me give you some overview how I keep track of bits of information and which tools are best suited for every day tasks.
Mind maps I&amp;rsquo;ve repeated this one several times: I like visualizing information.</description></item><item><title>Using Blockdiag with Pelican and liquid tags</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/11/21/using-blockdiag-with-pelican-and-liquid-tags/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/11/21/using-blockdiag-with-pelican-and-liquid-tags/</guid><description>After writing the previous article I thought I should share some Blockdiag plugin for Pelican. You can also check out the pull request.
blockdiag It&amp;rsquo;s basically a graphviz like utility with its own language (similar to DOT). You can create:
block diagrams sequence diagrams activity diagrams network diagrams rack diagrams packet diagrams It can save you a lot of time and has a pretty simple syntax. You can always test your code online using blockdiag&amp;rsquo;s interactive shell.</description></item><item><title>Using Graphviz with Pelican and liquid tags</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/11/13/using-graphviz-with-pelican-and-liquid-tags/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/11/13/using-graphviz-with-pelican-and-liquid-tags/</guid><description>I really like keeping things simple. And I also like generating figures from code using Graphviz. And since there was no Graphviz plugin for pelican I wrote my own one.
Using liquid tags I wanted to get my graphviz code rendered and automatically included as a base64 encoded image in my HTML code. I&amp;rsquo;ve created a pull request but you can find a fork at dorneanu-pelican.
Basically the tags works as follows:</description></item><item><title>HowTo: Write pentest reports the easy way</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/05/20/howto-write-pentest-reports-the-easy-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/05/20/howto-write-pentest-reports-the-easy-way/</guid><description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll try to share an idea I&amp;rsquo;ve had regarding pentest reports. Most of you surely have their own methods and tools to create nice looking reports after have done some pentesting. Since I try to keep things simple I&amp;rsquo;ll give you a rough idea how this could be done without Excel &amp;amp; Co.
Scenario Suppose you conduct a pentest and take notes during it. Afterwards you&amp;rsquo;ll be probably be copy&amp;amp;paste&amp;rsquo;integratedP the whole content into a layout or pre-defined document.</description></item><item><title>Unfancy dashboard using matplotlib</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/03/07/unfancy-dashboard-using-matplotlib/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/03/07/unfancy-dashboard-using-matplotlib/</guid><description>I was recently playing around with D3Â and discovered its dashboard posibilities.dashboarddude.comÂ has a nice compilation of really fancy dashboards (I was mainly interested in D3 but voila&amp;hellip; there are also other ways to do it).
Meanwhile I was remembered of old good IPython Notebook and its plotting features. This is what came out (You can find the code also on Github Gist: https://gist.github.com/dorneanu/9407737):
import datetime as dt import matplotlib.dates as mdates from mpl_toolkits.</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #18</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/22/links-of-the-week-#18/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/22/links-of-the-week-#18/</guid><description> Modern Userland Linux Exploitation Courseware: Also have a look at the presentation slides ELF Carver - Recovering Linux Binaries Catching and Understanding GSM-Signals SIM Card Forensics: An Introduction ZeroNights 2013 Materials exploit-exercises.com Encrypt the Web Report: Who&amp;rsquo;s Doing What ELF: A Linux executable walkthrough Creating pretty graphs in linux with gnuplot</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #13</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/10/18/links-of-the-week-#13/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/10/18/links-of-the-week-#13/</guid><description> CorkaMix: This is indeed insane!
Why We Hate Infographics (And Why You Should)
What Happens To Our Body After Drinking Coca Cola?: Coke anybody?
Kvasir: Network Vulnerability Management System</description></item></channel></rss>