<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ssh on blog.dornea.nu</title>
    <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/ssh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ssh on blog.dornea.nu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/ssh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 23</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/17/links-of-the-week-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/17/links-of-the-week-23/</guid>
      <description>InkTag: Secure Applications on an Untrusted Operating System
  Unicode Security Guide
  Hunting Botnets with ZMap
  EncFS Security Audit
  Hacking Tools Repository
  The Hacker Who Cracked the Code in Iron Man and The Social Network
  Operating System Tutorials
  The Jobless Ph.D. Generation
  The Holy Book of Passwords by Aram Bartholl
  Reconstructing the Cryptanalytic Attack behind the Flame Malware</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 4</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/07/links-of-the-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/07/links-of-the-week-4/</guid>
      <description>How the Prime Meridian Changed the World: Not technical stuff but worth reading.
  OpenSSH keys and the drunken bishop: Ever wondered about that visual fingerprint when generating SSH keys? Well this article brings some light on that. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried on my own and that&amp;rsquo;s fun: $ ssh -o VisualHostKey=yes victor@cia.gov -p 1337 Host key fingerprint is xxxxx +&amp;ndash;[ RSA 2048]&amp;mdash;-+ | .. | | . .. | | o .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 3</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/05/31/links-of-the-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/05/31/links-of-the-week-3/</guid>
      <description>Anatomy of a hack: How crackers ransack passwords like qeadzcwrsfxv1331 This is definetely link of the month! I never had to crack hashes in my life but this article is way the best introduction to the cracking/brute-forcing techniques. This is a must for all crackers out there (Thanks Marcin for the link). Yes, disassemble with Javap ALL OVER THE PLACE! Hacking Java Bytecode for Programmers (Part3): If the site is down check out this link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC: Connect to current desktop session using x11vnc and ssh</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/04/04/vnc-connect-to-current-desktop-session-using-x11vnc-and-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/04/04/vnc-connect-to-current-desktop-session-using-x11vnc-and-ssh/</guid>
      <description>x11vnc allows you to connect to real X displays without creating any new X session (fluxbox, twm, gnome etc.). It allows you to control the mouse, keyboard and X events remotely. I usually use it when friends of mine need help and I want to see what exactly they&amp;rsquo;re doing.
Make sure any **ssh server **is running on remote-hostand you have a vnc client installed on your localhost. Also make sure remote-host has x11vnc otherwise this won&amp;rsquo;t make sense at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: SSH-Tunnel over CorkScrew using Tor</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/05/howto-ssh-tunnel-over-corkscrew-using-tor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/05/howto-ssh-tunnel-over-corkscrew-using-tor/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays it seems like we&amp;rsquo;re loosing our privacy and are being taped by video cameras all over. The same applies to Internet surveillance: By daily traffic analysis you can find out who is talking to whom over a public network. This traffic allows others to track your click behaviour and interests. So if any mailicious guy has access to your network traffic (@work, @home …) he will try to find more information about you, like e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
