<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wifi on blog.dornea.nu</title>
    <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/wifi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wifi on blog.dornea.nu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/wifi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week #25</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/31/links-of-the-week-#25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/31/links-of-the-week-#25/</guid>
      <description>    NSA BIOS Backdoor a.k.a. God Mode Malware Part 1: DEITYBOUNCE
  Step-by-Step Guide To Decompiling Android Apps
  Untraceable Blog
  Continuously jam all wifi clients and access points within range
    eduroam WiFi security audit or why it is broken by design
    Java-based malware driving DDoS botnet infects Windows, Mac, Linux device
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week #8</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/09/links-of-the-week-#8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/09/links-of-the-week-#8/</guid>
      <description> Android Bug 82119321: A comprehensive description of the recent Android bug also known as the signature bug FOOAS: Fuck Of As A Service localtunnel: Access your local web server through the internet [A Tour Inside CloudFlare’s Latest Generation Servers}(http://blog.cloudflare.com/a-tour-inside-cloudflares-latest-generation-servers): Really impressive! Here’s What Wi-Fi Would Look Like If We Could See It Why I left OpenBSD: Remember self interview after leaving NetBSD? Function Hooking Part 1 – Hooking shared library function calls in Linux  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: SNAT/IP Masquerade between 2 wlan cards on Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/11/25/howto-snat/ip-masquerade-between-2-wlan-cards-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/11/25/howto-snat/ip-masquerade-between-2-wlan-cards-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>Although this is a quite minimalistic howto you should be able to do IP masquerading between your WLAN cards in less than 2 minutes. As I posted here I&amp;rsquo;d like to share use my WLAN cards to share one cards Internet connection with the other one. The following steps don&amp;rsquo;t apply only to wifi cards. The same commands should work on Ethernet cards too. Let&amp;rsquo;s start&amp;hellip;
The Big picture As you see you have 2 networks:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
