<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>events on blog.dornea.nu</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/events/</link><description>Recent content in events on blog.dornea.nu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>hack.lu conference 2016</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/10/21/hack.lu-conference-2016/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/10/21/hack.lu-conference-2016/</guid><description>This year I&amp;rsquo;ve attended the hack.lu conference in Luxembourg. Being actually for the first time there, I&amp;rsquo;ve had absolutely no expectations. In fact it was a really lovelly and warm athmosphere during the whole conference and I&amp;rsquo;ve met a lot of interesting persons.
Talks I think there were some realy good talks. Unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;ve seen only 1 because most of the time I was at the workshops practicing my reverse engineering skills.</description></item><item><title>The Digital Future in Berlin</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/05/11/the-digital-future-in-berlin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/05/11/the-digital-future-in-berlin/</guid><description>Like always the obligatory introduction to the event:
&amp;ldquo;The digital age began 75 years ago in Berlin, when Konrad Zuse created the world’s first functioning computer, the Z3. Since then computers have changed the world, much like the steam engine and the car before them. The biggest changes in connection with digitalisation are still to come.&amp;rdquo; (http://science-match.tagesspiegel.de/the-digital-future)
Digital Future? Well, that sounded like a whole bunch of topics to be presented at the event: Big Data, communication, data analysis, digital society, future computing, gaming, mobility, networks, optimization, privacy, simulation, security, visualization.</description></item><item><title>AWS Summit in Berlin 2016</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/04/12/aws-summit-in-berlin-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/04/12/aws-summit-in-berlin-2016/</guid><description>For the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve attended the AWS Summit in Berlin which against my expectations was very interesting. Not having much in common with AWS (at least not yet), from a security perspective the cloud still remains a very neglected threat to companies. As we all know there is some &amp;ldquo;rain&amp;rdquo; coming down from the cloud from time to time. And by &amp;ldquo;rain&amp;rdquo; I mean sensitive data which gets exposed due to misconfigured APIs, weak credentials or insecure applications.</description></item><item><title>BerlinSides 0x05</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/05/27/berlinsides-0x05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/05/27/berlinsides-0x05/</guid><description>The BerlinSides is a conference from hacker for hacker. This years motto was: &amp;hellip;you ain&amp;rsquo;t listening. All my greetings go to:
nullsecurity.net Aluc Universal Hall Team</description></item><item><title>CCC / 29C3</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2012/12/30/ccc-/-29c3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2012/12/30/ccc-/-29c3/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;The 29th Chaos Communication Congress (29C3) is an annual four-day conference on technology, society and utopia. The Congress offers lectures and workshops on a multitude of topics including (but not limited to) information technology and generally a critical-creative attitude towards technology and the discussion about the effects of technological advances on society.
For 29 years, the congress has been organized by the community and appreciates all kinds of participation.</description></item></channel></rss>