<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on blog.dornea.nu</title>
    <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on blog.dornea.nu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some forensics mini-challenge</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2017/02/01/some-forensics-mini-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2017/02/01/some-forensics-mini-challenge/</guid>
      <description>After reading this excellent article I&amp;rsquo;ve found this page. If you scroll down you&amp;rsquo;ll find the Apply section. Not that I wanted to apply for some job but I thought, it&amp;rsquo;d be challenging to find out the mail address:
 well, the email address is hidden below. Find the email and send your resume, solution walk-through and desired role.
 Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the message:
2c 54 2d f0 0d 2a 08 00 27 c3 59 62 08 00 45 00 01 a1 f3 33 40 00 40 06 bd 8d c0 a8 01 20 68 d2 5d fb 88 90 00 50 c9 c9 77 90 1f e5 d2 bd 50 18 00 e5 8a 29 00 00 50 4f 53 54 20 2f 63 61 72 65 65 72 20 48 54 54 50 2f 31 2e 31 0d 0a 48 6f 73 74 3a 20 77 77 77 2e 65 6c 74 74 61 6d 2e 63 6f 6d 2e 61 75 0d 0a 55 73 65 72 2d 41 67 65 6e 74 3a 20 65 6c 74 74 61 6d 20 72 6f 63 6b 73 21 0d 0a 41 63 63 65 70 74 2d 4c 61 6e 67 75 61 67 65 3a 20 65 6e 2d 55 53 2c 65 6e 3b 71 3d 30 2e 35 0d 0a 41 63 63 65 70 74 2d 45 6e 63 6f 64 69 6e 67 3a 20 67 7a 69 70 2c 20 64 65 66 6c 61 74 65 0d 0a 43 6f 6f 6b 69 65 3a 20 5a 57 31 68 61 57 77 39 4d 47 59 77 59 54 42 6a 4d 47 49 79 4e 54 41 77 4d 44 6b 78 4d 54 45 78 4d 44 51 77 4f 44 52 69 4d 44 59 77 59 54 41 34 4e 47 49 77 4e 44 45 77 0d 0a 43 6f 6e 74 65 6e 74 2d 54 79 70 65 3a 20 61 70 70 6c 69 63 61 74 69 6f 6e 2f 78 2d 77 77 77 2d 66 6f 72 6d 2d 75 72 6c 65 6e 63 6f 64 65 64 0d 0a 43 6f 6e 74 65 6e 74 2d 4c 65 6e 67 74 68 3a 20 38 31 0d 0a 43 6f 6e 6e 65 63 74 69 6f 6e 3a 20 63 6c 6f 73 65 0d 0a 0d 0a 71 3d 54 68 65 2b 65 6d 61 69 6c 2b 61 64 64 72 65 73 73 2b 69 73 2b 68 69 64 64 65 6e 2b 69 6e 2b 74 68 69 73 2b 72 65 71 75 65 73 74 26 62 6f 6e 75 73 3d 57 68 61 74 2b 69 73 2b 73 6f 75 72 63 65 2b 49 50 2b 61 64 64 72 65 73 73 0d 0a 0d 0a 00 Removing all the white spaces leads to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ringzer0 CTF - SysAdmin Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/10/30/ringzer0-ctf-sysadmin-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/10/30/ringzer0-ctf-sysadmin-linux/</guid>
      <description>SysAdmin Part 1 Let&amp;rsquo;s login to the machine:
$ sshpass -p VNZDDLq2x9qXCzVdABbR1HOtz ssh morpheus@for01.ringzer0team.com -p 13375 _ ____ __ _____(_)___ ____ _____ ___ _____/ __ \/ /____ ____ _____ ___ / ___/ / __ \/ __ `/_ / / _ \/ ___/ / / / __/ _ \/ __ `/ __ `__ \ / / / / / / / /_/ / / /_/ __/ / / /_/ / /_/ __/ /_/ / / / / / / /_/ /_/_/ /_/\__, / /___/\___/_/ \____/\__/\___/\__,_/_/ /_/ /_/ /____/ _ _ ___ _____ ___ ___ _ _ | (_)_ _ ___ / __|_ _| __| / _ \ &amp;#39; \| | | &amp;#39; \/ -_) | (__ | | | _| \___/_||_|_|_|_||_\___| \___| |_| |_| You have mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzing the hell out of conntrack tools</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/10/28/fuzzing-the-hell-out-of-conntrack-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/10/28/fuzzing-the-hell-out-of-conntrack-tools/</guid>
      <description>Fuzzing is nowadays the attack technique used by a lot of pentesters and security researchers. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking for vulnerabilities in media files (pictures, videos, audio stuff) or just binary files, fuzzing is the right approach if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to do some static code analysis or debug the hell out of your targets.
When it comes to fuzzing there are a few tools to mention that have established during the last years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No DNAT to localhost</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/notes/no-dnat-to-localhost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/notes/no-dnat-to-localhost/</guid>
      <description>Doing a simple port forwarding is actually a simple task:
$ iptables -A PREROUTING -p tcp --dport 80 -j REDIRECT --to-ports 8080 This would redirect all traffic from 80 to 8080. But if you have some firewall activated, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to allow both ports:
$ iptables -A INPUT -p tcp --dport 80 -j ALLOW $ iptables -A INPUT -p tcp --dport 8080 -j ALLOW Otherwise the port forwarding won&amp;rsquo;t work. But this is not the use case you want to achieve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Proxy Non-Proxy-Aware Android Applications through Burp</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/12/02/howto-proxy-non-proxy-aware-android-applications-through-burp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/12/02/howto-proxy-non-proxy-aware-android-applications-through-burp/</guid>
      <description>Proxying HTTP(s) traffic from Android devices through Burp should be actually no magic. Nevertheless you&amp;rsquo;ll have to take some important steps into consideration:
  Install Burps CA cert on the device
 I usually access Burp directly and download the cert file (cacert.crt) If Burp is listening on 192.168.1.1:8080, just go to http://192.168.1.1:8080/cert to download the cert Push this file to your device and install the certificate    Install ProxyDroid on Android</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 26</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/02/07/links-of-the-week-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/02/07/links-of-the-week-26/</guid>
      <description>Bitcoins the hard way: Using the raw Bitcoin protocol
  Modern Processors – A 90min guide
  The GSM security model
  Analyzing DarkComet in Memory
  Cryptography Breakthrough Could Make Software Unhackable
  Git tips from the trenches
  I Spent Two Hours Talking With the NSA&amp;rsquo;s Bigwigs. Here&amp;rsquo;s What Has Them Mad
  PRESS RELEASE: IRC NETWORKS UNDER SYSTEMATIC ATTACK FROM GOVERNMENTS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 25</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/31/links-of-the-week-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/31/links-of-the-week-25/</guid>
      <description>    NSA BIOS Backdoor a.k.a. God Mode Malware Part 1: DEITYBOUNCE
  Step-by-Step Guide To Decompiling Android Apps
  Untraceable Blog
  Continuously jam all wifi clients and access points within range
    eduroam WiFi security audit or why it is broken by design
    Java-based malware driving DDoS botnet infects Windows, Mac, Linux device
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 22</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/20/links-of-the-week-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/20/links-of-the-week-22/</guid>
      <description>  Remote Code Execution exploit in WordPress 3.5.1
  Dissection of Android malware MouaBad.P
  Linux: Keep An Eye On Your System With Glances Monitor
    DNA seen through the eyes of a coder
  Infection of biological DNA with digital Computer Code
    OpenBSD Exploit mitigation techniques
  RSA Key Extraction via Low-Bandwidth Acoustic Cryptanalysis
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 21</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/15/links-of-the-week-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/15/links-of-the-week-21/</guid>
      <description>    How We Decoded Some Nasty Multi-Level Encoded Malware
  LAYER 7 DDOS ATTACKS: DETECTION &amp;amp; MITIGATION
  Bypassing Internet Explorers Anti-Cross Site Scripting Filter
  On the 1st of January, 1998, Bjarne Stroustrup gave an interview to the IEEE Computer magazine.
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 19</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/29/links-of-the-week-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/29/links-of-the-week-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 18</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/22/links-of-the-week-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/22/links-of-the-week-18/</guid>
      <description> Modern Userland Linux Exploitation Courseware: Also have a look at the presentation slides ELF Carver - Recovering Linux Binaries Catching and Understanding GSM-Signals SIM Card Forensics: An Introduction ZeroNights 2013 Materials exploit-exercises.com Encrypt the Web Report: Who&amp;rsquo;s Doing What ELF: A Linux executable walkthrough Creating pretty graphs in linux with gnuplot  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 11</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/09/13/links-of-the-week-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/09/13/links-of-the-week-11/</guid>
      <description> nmap NSE hacking for IT security professionals The Wretched Google Interview Experience Why I left Google I Left Google And Lived To Happily Tell About It The NSA&amp;rsquo;s Cryptographic Capabilities Linux Trojan &amp;ldquo;Hand of Thief&amp;rdquo; ungloved You&amp;rsquo;re Smart. So What? GitHub is Not Your New Resume  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 10</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/23/links-of-the-week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/23/links-of-the-week-10/</guid>
      <description> 57 startup lessons Hacking Transcend WiFi SD Cards Hacking the OS X Kernel for Fun and Profiles Here&amp;rsquo;s what you find when you scan the entire Internet in an hour noteZilla: Interactive,clickable, sheet music Linux x86 Program Start Up (How the heck do we get to main()?) Average Income per Programming Language  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo, systemd, consolekit, udev and some failed system update</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/10/gentoo-systemd-consolekit-udev-and-some-failed-system-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/10/gentoo-systemd-consolekit-udev-and-some-failed-system-update/</guid>
      <description>OK, first some explanations:
 systemd is a modern sysvinit &amp;amp; RC replacement for Linux systems. It is supported in Gentoo as an alternate init system. (Source: http://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/Systemd) ConsoleKit is a framework for defining and tracking users, login sessions, and seats. (Source:http://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/ConsoleKit) udev is the device manager for the Linux kernel. Primarily, it manages device nodes in /devand handles all user space actions when adding/removing devices. Also have a look at eudeva gentoo fork of udev.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 8</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/09/links-of-the-week-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/09/links-of-the-week-8/</guid>
      <description> Android Bug 82119321: A comprehensive description of the recent Android bug also known as the signature bug FOOAS: Fuck Of As A Service localtunnel: Access your local web server through the internet [A Tour Inside CloudFlare’s Latest Generation Servers}(http://blog.cloudflare.com/a-tour-inside-cloudflares-latest-generation-servers): Really impressive! Here’s What Wi-Fi Would Look Like If We Could See It Why I left OpenBSD: Remember self interview after leaving NetBSD? Function Hooking Part 1 – Hooking shared library function calls in Linux  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 4</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/07/links-of-the-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/07/links-of-the-week-4/</guid>
      <description>How the Prime Meridian Changed the World: Not technical stuff but worth reading.
  OpenSSH keys and the drunken bishop: Ever wondered about that visual fingerprint when generating SSH keys? Well this article brings some light on that. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried on my own and that&amp;rsquo;s fun: $ ssh -o VisualHostKey=yes victor@cia.gov -p 1337 Host key fingerprint is xxxxx +&amp;ndash;[ RSA 2048]&amp;mdash;-+ | .. | | . .. | | o .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Links of the Week (LOW) 1</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/05/17/introducing-links-of-the-week-low-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/05/17/introducing-links-of-the-week-low-1/</guid>
      <description>A binary analysis, count me if you can:Really impressive skills! See how cracking can be a lot of fun! AttackVector Linux:Combine BackTrack/Kali, TOR and Tails for high anonymity. I liked that one: *Nmap can&#39;t UDP via Tor* Skype Big Brother Microsoft is watching you:You should take that into consideration before having your next Skype session. Writing a XSS Worm: Really nice one! Hackersh 0.2 released:You should definitely give it a try!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My own cheap NAS - the OpenWRT way</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/03/19/my-own-cheap-nas-the-openwrt-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/03/19/my-own-cheap-nas-the-openwrt-way/</guid>
      <description>Introducing my TP-Link TL-WR1043ND:
Summary  OS: Linux OpenWrt 2.6.32.25 #1 Fri Nov 19 20:27:50 PST 2010 mips GNU/Linux CPU: system type : Atheros AR9132 rev 2 machine : TP-LINK TL-WR1043ND processor : 0 cpu model : MIPS 24Kc V7.4  Filesystems root@OpenWrt:~# df -Ph Filesystem Size Used Available Capacity Mounted on /dev/root 2.1M 2.1M 0 100% /rom tmpfs 14.4M 232.0K 14.2M 2% /tmp tmpfs 512.0K 0 512.0K 0% /dev /dev/sda1 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: SNAT/IP Masquerade between 2 wlan cards on Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/11/25/howto-snat/ip-masquerade-between-2-wlan-cards-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/11/25/howto-snat/ip-masquerade-between-2-wlan-cards-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>Although this is a quite minimalistic howto you should be able to do IP masquerading between your WLAN cards in less than 2 minutes. As I posted here I&amp;rsquo;d like to share use my WLAN cards to share one cards Internet connection with the other one. The following steps don&amp;rsquo;t apply only to wifi cards. The same commands should work on Ethernet cards too. Let&amp;rsquo;s start&amp;hellip;
The Big picture As you see you have 2 networks:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Create new Debian domU using Xen on *BSD</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/22/howto-create-new-debian-domu-using-xen-on-bsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/22/howto-create-new-debian-domu-using-xen-on-bsd/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial you&amp;rsquo;ll get detailed information how to setup a fully functionable Debian Lenny system using virtualization software Xen. This entry was written due to high frustration caused by unreliable/outdated articles on the Internet and uncompleted tutorials. This here should be an attempt to describe the installation process completely and provide additional information which might help you solve common problems. The domU system we&amp;rsquo;d like to setup (in our case Debian) provides a neat netboot installer which supports Xen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetBSD, Linux, Xen - Does it work?</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/11/14/netbsd-linux-xen-does-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/11/14/netbsd-linux-xen-does-it-work/</guid>
      <description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my impressions I made with Xen during the last weeks. I met Xen a few months ago but due to general lack of interest I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the chance to give it a try.Para-virtualization - why bother at all? There were actually no significant reasons why I should use virtualization. But then it started with this thread, followed by this one. The really fascinating - and tough quite useful - aspect of virtualization consists of the hardware access policy which is implemented by the virtualization host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mod2Exec - Execute modules </title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2008/11/26/mod2exec-execute-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2008/11/26/mod2exec-execute-modules/</guid>
      <description>Einleitung Wir leben in einer Zeit, in der Dynamik sowie Flexibilität eine große Rolle spielen. Wir alle besitzen bestimmte Fähigkeiten, die in bestimmten Situationen zum Einsatz kommen können. Das heißt, der Mensch braucht diese nur zur richtigen Zeit „aufzurufen“. Genauso soll ein Kernel, das Herzstück eines Betriebssystems, auch funktionieren: Die aktuelle
Systemkonfiguration wird überprüft und Module werden hochgeladen. Damit werden dem Kernel Schnittstellen zur Verfügung gestellt, die zur Steuerung der Hardware etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viral Infections on Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2008/11/26/viral-infections-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2008/11/26/viral-infections-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>Einleitung Wir leben in einem digitalen Zeitalter, in dem sich Technologien rasch weiterentwickeln und deren Präsenz für uns Menschen eine immer größer werdende Rolle spielt. Gleichzeitig erfahren wir eine Zunahme der Computer-Kriminalität, geprägt von mafiösen Strukturen, die sich zum Ziel gesetzt haben, Informationen im Eigeninteresse zu sammeln.
Die Wichtigkeit dieser Informationen variiert je nach Art des Angriffs und reicht von der IP-Adresse des Nutzers bis zur Kreditkarten- oder Versicherungsnummer. Die dabei verwendeten</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
