<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>netbsd on blog.dornea.nu</title>
    <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/netbsd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in netbsd on blog.dornea.nu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/netbsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 8</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/09/links-of-the-week-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/09/links-of-the-week-8/</guid>
      <description> Android Bug 82119321: A comprehensive description of the recent Android bug also known as the signature bug FOOAS: Fuck Of As A Service localtunnel: Access your local web server through the internet [A Tour Inside CloudFlare’s Latest Generation Servers}(http://blog.cloudflare.com/a-tour-inside-cloudflares-latest-generation-servers): Really impressive! Here’s What Wi-Fi Would Look Like If We Could See It Why I left OpenBSD: Remember self interview after leaving NetBSD? Function Hooking Part 1 – Hooking shared library function calls in Linux  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 6</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/28/links-of-the-week-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/28/links-of-the-week-6/</guid>
      <description>This weeks links:
 Self interview after leaving the NetBSD board: I still like NetBSD a lot but what Julio writes in his blog makes me feel sad about the whole project. Free Raspberry Pi Hosting: Really interesting idea. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see some day a whole P2P network build upon raspberry pi&amp;rsquo;s. Google Trends: Get a real-time view on what&amp;rsquo;s being searched on Google right now. Really impressive! Learn Git Branching: Learn how Git&amp;rsquo;s branching really works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenBSD, FreeBSD, NetBSD - I do love beasts!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/03/21/openbsd-freebsd-netbsd-i-do-love-beasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/03/21/openbsd-freebsd-netbsd-i-do-love-beasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It all starts with virtualisation! Since there is no BSD at all on my laptop, I thought I should give the most important ones a chance: FreeBSD, OpenBSD and NetBSD. Although there were several rumours afloat – related to complexity factors (installation, configuration etc.) – I had absolutely no problem setting up *BSD with X11(!!!). Besides that I had a look at the packaging systems provided within each BSD. My conclusion: They are pretty much the same: &lt;strong&gt;make install&lt;/strong&gt; and basta. Here some screenshots:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rm -rf / and some kernel panic</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/26/rm-rf-/-and-some-kernel-panic/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/26/rm-rf-/-and-some-kernel-panic/</guid>
      <description>If you ever had in mind to rm -rf /: DON&amp;rsquo;T! Even for its funny aspect, it isn&amp;rsquo;t worth doing such a stupid thing. Well I did it..At least not intentionally. I remember I was going to remove some ordinary directory and then I must have misspelled the last argument (directory name). Luckily I was able to notice the tragedy and cancel the command by ^C. F\***! What should I now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Create new Debian domU using Xen on *BSD</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/22/howto-create-new-debian-domu-using-xen-on-bsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/22/howto-create-new-debian-domu-using-xen-on-bsd/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial you&amp;rsquo;ll get detailed information how to setup a fully functionable Debian Lenny system using virtualization software Xen. This entry was written due to high frustration caused by unreliable/outdated articles on the Internet and uncompleted tutorials. This here should be an attempt to describe the installation process completely and provide additional information which might help you solve common problems. The domU system we&amp;rsquo;d like to setup (in our case Debian) provides a neat netboot installer which supports Xen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Qemu networking on NetBSD</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/01/howto-qemu-networking-on-netbsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/01/howto-qemu-networking-on-netbsd/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial I&amp;rsquo;d like to give you some useful examples how to configure network when using Qemu as virtualization machine. The videos in this HowTo were taken on a NetBSD-5_STABLE/amd64 machine using Qemu 0.11.1. **Attention: **On my system I&amp;rsquo;ve used a patched version of Qemu as reported here. However you can use the fd= option to specify an open socket to be used. Example:
$ qemu -cdrom [iso file] -net nic -net tap,fd=3 3&amp;lt;&amp;gt;/dev/tap0 Using this example `tap0″ should be created before the qemu command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetBSD, Linux, Xen - Does it work?</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/11/14/netbsd-linux-xen-does-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/11/14/netbsd-linux-xen-does-it-work/</guid>
      <description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my impressions I made with Xen during the last weeks. I met Xen a few months ago but due to general lack of interest I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the chance to give it a try.Para-virtualization - why bother at all? There were actually no significant reasons why I should use virtualization. But then it started with this thread, followed by this one. The really fascinating - and tough quite useful - aspect of virtualization consists of the hardware access policy which is implemented by the virtualization host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep your system up2date!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/09/07/keep-your-system-up2date/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/09/07/keep-your-system-up2date/</guid>
      <description>Due to NetBSD’s great packaging system, software gets updated very frequently. It is very important to have a clean and safe system running and no outdated packages on your system. They might be vulnerable to recently discovered bugs and affect your systems’s security and performance. After updating the package tree (see documentation), I usually update my whole system by running:
$ pkg_chk -su Actually there is nothing wrong about that. Yet there is one big problem, which caused me to seek for another updating mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetBSD, kernel downgrade and some voodoo!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/20/netbsd-kernel-downgrade-and-some-voodoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/20/netbsd-kernel-downgrade-and-some-voodoo/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you still remember my ACPI suspend/resume problems a few months ago. I once suspended my Linux system to RAM and forgotten to make a proper shutdown. After a while the battery discharged and my laptop was out of power. After some reboots (there were about 15 tries) I finally managed it to boot my system again. Some BIOS error occured every time. That error still keeps my busy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoWPAtty 4.2 for NetBSD</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/07/22/cowpatty-4.2-for-netbsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/07/22/cowpatty-4.2-for-netbsd/</guid>
      <description>From http://wirelessdefence.org/Contents/coWPAttyMain.htm:
 coWPAtty is designed to audit the pre-shared key (PSK) selection for WPA networks based on the TKIP protocol. - Joshua Wright.
 Since I had problems installing/compiling cowpatty, I had to modify the Makefile and several include-lines in some files. Currently I&amp;rsquo;m using NetBSD/Amd64. Feel free to modify the files at your needs. Download here!
Edit: As stated here, there is a newer version, 4.3. I edited the Makefile and created a new tarball.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetBSD rulez!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/05/05/netbsd-rulez/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/05/05/netbsd-rulez/</guid>
      <description>I just started installing NetBSD on my 2nd laptop. Everything works like a charm! (thanks L. for your support xD) I was kind of sick of Linux/Debian and wanted to try something new. I made my decision and installed NetBSD due to its high portability: &amp;ldquo;Of course it runs NetBSD!&amp;rdquo; I heard Thinkpads are very well supported by NetBSD but I need to accomodate to the new system and do some testings before installing it on my main working machine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
