<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>crypto on blog.dornea.nu</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/crypto/</link><description>Recent content in crypto on blog.dornea.nu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ringzer0 CTF - JavaScript challenges</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/10/29/ringzer0-ctf-javascript-challenges/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/10/29/ringzer0-ctf-javascript-challenges/</guid><description>These challenges were quite tricky since they didn&amp;rsquo;t focus only on the JavaScript language itself but also on all kind of stuff you can do with JavaScript: Crypto, obfuscation etc. I think they were a good opportunity to learn more about the language itself and get some ideas how JavaScript obfuscation techniques work.
Level 1: Client side validation is bad! Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the source code:
// Look&amp;#39;s like weak JavaScript auth script :) $(&amp;#34;.</description></item><item><title>OpenVPN for paranoids</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/11/17/openvpn-for-paranoids/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/11/17/openvpn-for-paranoids/</guid><description>Continuing my admin series this time I&amp;rsquo;d like to setup a VPN using OpenVPN as user-based VPN solution. Unlike IPSec solutions which require IPSec on both (server and client) sides, securing the VPN tunnel by OpenSSL is a more preferable option.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll try to show which steps have to be taken in order to:
secure the communication channel use up-to-date (and secure!) TLS configurations prevent information leaks when the VPN tunnel is down At least for the last one some additional steps are required to route your traffic only through the VPN tunnel.</description></item><item><title>Manage PKI using OpenSSL</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/10/02/manage-pki-using-openssl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/10/02/manage-pki-using-openssl/</guid><description>In the previous X.509 related post I&amp;rsquo;ve had a look at the internals of a X.509 certficate. This time I want to setup my own PKI using some open source software. This post is a preparation for setting up a VPN using OpenVPN.
Before implementing the PKI let&amp;rsquo;s have a look what a PKI should definitely include (make sure you have a look at the Wikipedia entry):
certificate authority (CA) has a public and a private key used to digitally sign certificates registration authority (RA) verify identify of users requesting information from the CA certificate management system probably the most important component Revision CA types There are several types of CAs:</description></item><item><title>Validating and pinning X.509 certificates</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/05/24/validating-and-pinning-x.509-certificates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/05/24/validating-and-pinning-x.509-certificates/</guid><description>In times of NSA, surveillance and data privacy, protecting your data has become an essential part of your every day life. A good understanding of basic principles is half the battle. In this post I just wanted to have look at SSL/TLS from a developer point of view but also from an users one. On the one hand I wanted to use openssl as a CLI utility to inspect and validate X.</description></item><item><title>On Java, OpenSSL, Crypto, Blowfish and stuff</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/07/01/on-java-openssl-crypto-blowfish-and-stuff/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/07/01/on-java-openssl-crypto-blowfish-and-stuff/</guid><description>During some Android malware analysis I came along some Java routines which were meant to decrypt/encrypt some content. Nothing special about it. The key had to be extracted from a file and the encrypted file was in Base64. After unsuccessfully trying openssl in order to decrypt the file I decided to make some further investigations.
In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll have a look how Python, Java and openssl (command line utility) implement Blowfish in CBC mode.</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #27</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/02/14/links-of-the-week-#27/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/02/14/links-of-the-week-#27/</guid><description> When Random Isn’t Random Enough: Lessons from an Online Poker Exploit
Technical Details Behind a 400Gbps NTP Amplification DDoS Attack
Absolute Computatrace revisited
Burp Co2
Porting Applications to 64bit ARM
Price and Feature Comparison of Web Application Scanners
GoLismero 2.0 Beta 3
vulnhub.com
faces.io</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #26</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/02/07/links-of-the-week-#26/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/02/07/links-of-the-week-#26/</guid><description>Bitcoins the hard way: Using the raw Bitcoin protocol
Modern Processors – A 90min guide
The GSM security model
Analyzing DarkComet in Memory
Cryptography Breakthrough Could Make Software Unhackable
Git tips from the trenches
I Spent Two Hours Talking With the NSA&amp;rsquo;s Bigwigs. Here&amp;rsquo;s What Has Them Mad
PRESS RELEASE: IRC NETWORKS UNDER SYSTEMATIC ATTACK FROM GOVERNMENTS</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #23</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/17/links-of-the-week-#23/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/17/links-of-the-week-#23/</guid><description>InkTag: Secure Applications on an Untrusted Operating System
Unicode Security Guide
Hunting Botnets with ZMap
EncFS Security Audit
Hacking Tools Repository
The Hacker Who Cracked the Code in Iron Man and The Social Network
Operating System Tutorials
The Jobless Ph.D. Generation
The Holy Book of Passwords by Aram Bartholl
Reconstructing the Cryptanalytic Attack behind the Flame Malware</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #22</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/20/links-of-the-week-#22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/20/links-of-the-week-#22/</guid><description> Remote Code Execution exploit in WordPress 3.5.1
Dissection of Android malware MouaBad.P
Linux: Keep An Eye On Your System With Glances Monitor
DNA seen through the eyes of a coder
Infection of biological DNA with digital Computer Code
OpenBSD Exploit mitigation techniques
RSA Key Extraction via Low-Bandwidth Acoustic Cryptanalysis</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #21</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/15/links-of-the-week-#21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/15/links-of-the-week-#21/</guid><description> How We Decoded Some Nasty Multi-Level Encoded Malware
LAYER 7 DDOS ATTACKS: DETECTION &amp;amp; MITIGATION
Bypassing Internet Explorers Anti-Cross Site Scripting Filter
On the 1st of January, 1998, Bjarne Stroustrup gave an interview to the IEEE Computer magazine.</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #20</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/06/links-of-the-week-#20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/06/links-of-the-week-#20/</guid><description> Android Root Detection Techniques Shmoocon 2013 Playlist INSECURE Mag 40 A society of phone Zombies Encrypted peer-to-peer web application platform for decentralized, privacy-preserving applications The UNIX system family tree: Research and BSD Found: Hacker server storing two million pilfered passwords Burp/Zap plugin: generator script</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #19</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/29/links-of-the-week-#19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/29/links-of-the-week-#19/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Links of the Week #18</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/22/links-of-the-week-#18/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/22/links-of-the-week-#18/</guid><description> Modern Userland Linux Exploitation Courseware: Also have a look at the presentation slides ELF Carver - Recovering Linux Binaries Catching and Understanding GSM-Signals SIM Card Forensics: An Introduction ZeroNights 2013 Materials exploit-exercises.com Encrypt the Web Report: Who&amp;rsquo;s Doing What ELF: A Linux executable walkthrough Creating pretty graphs in linux with gnuplot</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #15</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/01/links-of-the-week-#15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/01/links-of-the-week-#15/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://getpocket.com/redirect?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.exploit-db.com%2Fexploits%2F29290%2F">Apache / PHP 5.x Remote Code Execution Exploit&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.embedded.com/design/safety-and-security/4396040/An-Introduction-to-Elliptic-Curve-Cryptography">An introduction to elliptic curve cryptography&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://blog.cloudflare.com/a-relatively-easy-to-understand-primer-on-elliptic-curve-cryptography">A (Relatively Easy To Understand) Primer on Elliptic Curve Cryptography&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://qandwhat.apps.runkite.com/i-failed-a-twitter-interview/">I Failed a Twitter Interview&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/oct/24/former-spy-chief-overheard-acela-twitter">Former spy chief overheard giving off-the-record interview from Acela train&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #11</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/09/13/links-of-the-week-#11/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/09/13/links-of-the-week-#11/</guid><description> nmap NSE hacking for IT security professionals The Wretched Google Interview Experience Why I left Google I Left Google And Lived To Happily Tell About It The NSA&amp;rsquo;s Cryptographic Capabilities Linux Trojan &amp;ldquo;Hand of Thief&amp;rdquo; ungloved You&amp;rsquo;re Smart. So What? GitHub is Not Your New Resume</description></item><item><title>HowTo: Keep your passwords safe using SQLite and SQLCipher</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/07/28/howto-keep-your-passwords-safe-using-sqlite-and-sqlcipher/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/07/28/howto-keep-your-passwords-safe-using-sqlite-and-sqlcipher/</guid><description>I was recently doing some hacks and realized that there must be a way to store gained information in a secure manner. I usually encrypt sensitive information (like passwords, accounts etc.) using GPG. But that&amp;rsquo;s quite unhandy: You always need your private key and the encrypted data is stored unencrypted on the device (unless you&amp;rsquo;re using full disk encryption which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem since data is stored encrypted on the device).</description></item><item><title>HowTo: Full-Encrypt data using Gentoo,Luks and initramfs</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/03/07/howto-full-encrypt-data-using-gentooluks-and-initramfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/03/07/howto-full-encrypt-data-using-gentooluks-and-initramfs/</guid><description>Since last post many things have changed. No more NetBSD on my laptop (this has to do with several things, I&amp;rsquo;ll write about in a future post): I had to fall in love with Gentoo! I&amp;rsquo;ll try to give you some quick overview related to this posts title: Encryption under Gentoo using Luks.
There are serveral (good!) tutorials out there. Among these I&amp;rsquo;ve used:
&amp;lt;td&amp;gt; There you'll get a lot of information related to the topic.</description></item><item><title>HowTo: RsynCrypto - The backup jewel</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/06/25/howto-rsyncrypto-the-backup-jewel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/06/25/howto-rsyncrypto-the-backup-jewel/</guid><description>Nowadays it is essential to backup your data and keep it safe in case of a data loss event. The most common way to backup (private) data is to use a remote server where you can upload your data. Certainly you want to keep it safe and private So how do you want to guarantee the privacy of the files stored? Upload it to the server and encrypt it afterwards?! Somehow you want to automate this backup process so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to do nothing than running the backup script.</description></item></channel></rss>