<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>update on blog.dornea.nu</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/update/</link><description>Recent content in update on blog.dornea.nu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The iOS 8.1.3 fiasco</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/02/26/the-ios-8.1.3-fiasco/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/02/26/the-ios-8.1.3-fiasco/</guid><description>From time to time we all seem to ignore the &amp;ldquo;voice of reason&amp;rdquo; and tend to unconsidered actions. This will be a short summary of what could go wrong when one is forced to quick reactions which will result in chaos.
All started with an iPad Air. I have jailbroken the device from the very first touch. That time iOS 7.x was installed and a jailbreak was available for that specific version (iOS 7.</description></item><item><title>Gentoo, systemd, consolekit, udev and some failed system update</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/10/gentoo-systemd-consolekit-udev-and-some-failed-system-update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/10/gentoo-systemd-consolekit-udev-and-some-failed-system-update/</guid><description>OK, first some explanations:
systemd is a modern sysvinit &amp;amp; RC replacement for Linux systems. It is supported in Gentoo as an alternate init system. (Source: http://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/Systemd) ConsoleKit is a framework for defining and tracking users, login sessions, and seats. (Source:http://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/ConsoleKit) udev is the device manager for the Linux kernel. Primarily, it manages device nodes in /devand handles all user space actions when adding/removing devices. Also have a look at eudeva gentoo fork of udev.</description></item><item><title>Keep your system up2date!</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/09/07/keep-your-system-up2date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/09/07/keep-your-system-up2date/</guid><description>Due to NetBSD’s great packaging system, software gets updated very frequently. It is very important to have a clean and safe system running and no outdated packages on your system. They might be vulnerable to recently discovered bugs and affect your systems’s security and performance. After updating the package tree (see documentation), I usually update my whole system by running:
$ pkg_chk -su Actually there is nothing wrong about that. Yet there is one big problem, which caused me to seek for another updating mechanism.</description></item><item><title>NetBSD, kernel downgrade and some voodoo!</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/20/netbsd-kernel-downgrade-and-some-voodoo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/20/netbsd-kernel-downgrade-and-some-voodoo/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you still remember my ACPI suspend/resume problems a few months ago. I once suspended my Linux system to RAM and forgotten to make a proper shutdown. After a while the battery discharged and my laptop was out of power. After some reboots (there were about 15 tries) I finally managed it to boot my system again. Some BIOS error occured every time. That error still keeps my busy.</description></item></channel></rss>