<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>networking on blog.dornea.nu</title>
    <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in networking on blog.dornea.nu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some forensics mini-challenge</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2017/02/01/some-forensics-mini-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2017/02/01/some-forensics-mini-challenge/</guid>
      <description>After reading this excellent article I&amp;rsquo;ve found this page. If you scroll down you&amp;rsquo;ll find the Apply section. Not that I wanted to apply for some job but I thought, it&amp;rsquo;d be challenging to find out the mail address:
 well, the email address is hidden below. Find the email and send your resume, solution walk-through and desired role.
 Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the message:
2c 54 2d f0 0d 2a 08 00 27 c3 59 62 08 00 45 00 01 a1 f3 33 40 00 40 06 bd 8d c0 a8 01 20 68 d2 5d fb 88 90 00 50 c9 c9 77 90 1f e5 d2 bd 50 18 00 e5 8a 29 00 00 50 4f 53 54 20 2f 63 61 72 65 65 72 20 48 54 54 50 2f 31 2e 31 0d 0a 48 6f 73 74 3a 20 77 77 77 2e 65 6c 74 74 61 6d 2e 63 6f 6d 2e 61 75 0d 0a 55 73 65 72 2d 41 67 65 6e 74 3a 20 65 6c 74 74 61 6d 20 72 6f 63 6b 73 21 0d 0a 41 63 63 65 70 74 2d 4c 61 6e 67 75 61 67 65 3a 20 65 6e 2d 55 53 2c 65 6e 3b 71 3d 30 2e 35 0d 0a 41 63 63 65 70 74 2d 45 6e 63 6f 64 69 6e 67 3a 20 67 7a 69 70 2c 20 64 65 66 6c 61 74 65 0d 0a 43 6f 6f 6b 69 65 3a 20 5a 57 31 68 61 57 77 39 4d 47 59 77 59 54 42 6a 4d 47 49 79 4e 54 41 77 4d 44 6b 78 4d 54 45 78 4d 44 51 77 4f 44 52 69 4d 44 59 77 59 54 41 34 4e 47 49 77 4e 44 45 77 0d 0a 43 6f 6e 74 65 6e 74 2d 54 79 70 65 3a 20 61 70 70 6c 69 63 61 74 69 6f 6e 2f 78 2d 77 77 77 2d 66 6f 72 6d 2d 75 72 6c 65 6e 63 6f 64 65 64 0d 0a 43 6f 6e 74 65 6e 74 2d 4c 65 6e 67 74 68 3a 20 38 31 0d 0a 43 6f 6e 6e 65 63 74 69 6f 6e 3a 20 63 6c 6f 73 65 0d 0a 0d 0a 71 3d 54 68 65 2b 65 6d 61 69 6c 2b 61 64 64 72 65 73 73 2b 69 73 2b 68 69 64 64 65 6e 2b 69 6e 2b 74 68 69 73 2b 72 65 71 75 65 73 74 26 62 6f 6e 75 73 3d 57 68 61 74 2b 69 73 2b 73 6f 75 72 63 65 2b 49 50 2b 61 64 64 72 65 73 73 0d 0a 0d 0a 00 Removing all the white spaces leads to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzing the hell out of conntrack tools</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/10/28/fuzzing-the-hell-out-of-conntrack-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/10/28/fuzzing-the-hell-out-of-conntrack-tools/</guid>
      <description>Fuzzing is nowadays the attack technique used by a lot of pentesters and security researchers. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking for vulnerabilities in media files (pictures, videos, audio stuff) or just binary files, fuzzing is the right approach if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to do some static code analysis or debug the hell out of your targets.
When it comes to fuzzing there are a few tools to mention that have established during the last years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribute your backups using git-annex</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/06/16/distribute-your-backups-using-git-annex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/06/16/distribute-your-backups-using-git-annex/</guid>
      <description>Backuping a whole bunch of photos and videos might be a difficult task. Taking care of the consistency of your backups is even more complicated task. Besides that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to have your backups at a single place, thus mitigating the impact of a single point of data loss.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using git-annex for some years but not like a pro user, rather than &amp;ldquo;it just works&amp;rdquo;. Meanwhile I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of ownCloud and I&amp;rsquo;ve liked it because one can access its data via web, mobile client or whatever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No DNAT to localhost</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/01/20/no-dnat-to-localhost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/01/20/no-dnat-to-localhost/</guid>
      <description>Doing a simple port forwarding is actually a simple task:
$ iptables -A PREROUTING -p tcp --dport 80 -j REDIRECT --to-ports 8080 This would redirect all traffic from 80 to 8080. But if you have some firewall activated, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to allow both ports:
$ iptables -A INPUT -p tcp --dport 80 -j ALLOW $ iptables -A INPUT -p tcp --dport 8080 -j ALLOW Otherwise the port forwarding won&amp;rsquo;t work. But this is not the use case you want to achieve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN for paranoids </title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/11/17/openvpn-for-paranoids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/11/17/openvpn-for-paranoids/</guid>
      <description>Continuing my admin series this time I&amp;rsquo;d like to setup a VPN using OpenVPN  as user-based VPN solution. Unlike IPSec solutions which require IPSec on both (server and client) sides, securing the VPN tunnel by OpenSSL is a more preferable option.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll try to show which steps have to be taken in order to:
 secure the communication channel use up-to-date (and secure!) TLS configurations prevent information leaks when the VPN tunnel is down  At least for the last one some additional steps are required to route your traffic only through the VPN tunnel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced inter VLAN switching using Cisco</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/11/06/advanced-inter-vlan-switching-using-cisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/11/06/advanced-inter-vlan-switching-using-cisco/</guid>
      <description>Continuing my CCNA journey I&amp;rsquo;d like to address inter VLAN switching in a more detailed way. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll configure my previous topology to use VTP and let STP prevent frame looping and other &amp;ldquo;anomalies&amp;rdquo; on Layer 2.
Updated network topology %%blockdiag # &amp;lt;!-- collapse=True --&amp;gt; diagram admin {↔ PC1 [shape = &amp;#34;cisco.pc&amp;#34;]; PC2 [shape = &amp;#34;cisco.pc&amp;#34;]; PC3 [shape = &amp;#34;cisco.pc&amp;#34;]; PC4 [shape = &amp;#34;cisco.pc&amp;#34;]; PC5 [shape = &amp;#34;cisco.pc&amp;#34;]; PC6 [shape = &amp;#34;cisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Layer 2 Switching using Cisco Packet Tracer</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/10/21/basic-layer-2-switching-using-cisco-packet-tracer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/10/21/basic-layer-2-switching-using-cisco-packet-tracer/</guid>
      <description>As a pseudo-preparation for my CCNA exam I wanted to sum up some of the basic configuration steps related to Cisco switches. Although I won&amp;rsquo;t handle every topic related to Layer 2, I will assume you have already some network knowledge. The main reason for this post is to show how to setup a really small network infrastructure and configure its components. For my purposes I have used Cisco&amp;rsquo;s Packet Tracer to simulate the network which I highly recommend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gethostbyname vs. getaddrinfo</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/04/30/gethostbyname-vs.-getaddrinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/04/30/gethostbyname-vs.-getaddrinfo/</guid>
      <description>After started coding in C again I&amp;rsquo;ve had a look at some basic network stuff like: socket(), connect() etc. In order to resolve domain names, one was used to use gethostbyname(). I&amp;rsquo;ve used this function in all my previous C projects but this one seems to be out-dated as the main page states:
The gethostbyname*(), gethostbyaddr*(), herror(), and hstrerror() functions are obsolete. Applications should use getaddrinfo(3), getnameinfo(3), and gai_strerror(3) instead.  The really bad thing about gethostbyname is the fact that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support IPv6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>usd AG Hacker challenge 2015 - Solutions</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/03/18/usd-ag-hacker-challenge-2015-solutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/03/18/usd-ag-hacker-challenge-2015-solutions/</guid>
      <description>usd AG has announced a hacking challenge I have participated at. The target system was available at http://82.195.79.41/. Now let me sum up thg steps that have been required in order to get all 6 tokens.
# &amp;lt;!-- collapse=True --&amp;gt; import pandas as pd import sqlite3 import binascii Scratch the surface Let&amp;rsquo;s first conduct a nmap scan to see which ports are open.
%%bash nmap -A -T4 82.195.79.41 Starting Nmap 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A practical guide to Advanced Networking</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/01/08/a-practical-guide-to-advanced-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/01/08/a-practical-guide-to-advanced-networking/</guid>
      <description>During the past months I was from time to time reading all kind of stuff related to networking and security. During this process I came accross this book:
{% img http://dl.dornea.nu/img/2015/3b9c034b88c3d5ea44bd4d6bc4436c0f.jpg %}
I found this book to be very comprehensive and very modern in sense of current topics across the &amp;ldquo;network universe&amp;rdquo;. If you ever wanted to get a more deep insight in how routers communicate with each other or how to setup a VoIP infrastructure, this book is a must.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 - Personal review</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/12/22/2014-personal-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/12/22/2014-personal-review/</guid>
      <description>Well, where should I start? Looking back at my blog archives I&amp;rsquo;ve realized 2014 &amp;ldquo;year of the mobile apps&amp;rdquo; - at least for me. I was heavily involved in analyzing mobile applications: Android and iOS. For the first time in my whole infosec career path I was disassembling iOS applications and doing stuff (binary analysis) I was used to (some years ago). Besides doing a lot of mobile apps analysis, I was pretty much involved in structuring and hacking data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Proxy Non-Proxy-Aware Android Applications through Burp</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/12/02/howto-proxy-non-proxy-aware-android-applications-through-burp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/12/02/howto-proxy-non-proxy-aware-android-applications-through-burp/</guid>
      <description>Proxying HTTP(s) traffic from Android devices through Burp should be actually no magic. Nevertheless you&amp;rsquo;ll have to take some important steps into consideration:
  Install Burps CA cert on the device
 I usually access Burp directly and download the cert file (cacert.crt) If Burp is listening on 192.168.1.1:8080, just go to http://192.168.1.1:8080/cert to download the cert Push this file to your device and install the certificate    Install ProxyDroid on Android</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generate all IP addresses from ASN</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/09/17/generate-all-ip-addresses-from-asn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/09/17/generate-all-ip-addresses-from-asn/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you need to know if a certain IP (or several ones) are within an IP range or belong to a certain ASN. Let&amp;rsquo;s give it a try and generate all possible IP addresses for telekom.de.
$ dig telekom.de ... telekom.de. 86346 IN A 46.29.100.76 ... Now let&amp;rsquo;s find out the ASN:
$ whois 46.29.100.76 | grep origin origin: AS34086 Now ask RIPE for the IP ranges:
$ whois -h whois.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Androguard with Docker</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/09/12/howto-androguard-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/09/12/howto-androguard-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Meanwhile I think I&amp;rsquo;ve felt in love with Androguard. I love its Pythonic way handling things and its visualizations features. As many of you have noticed, you can run Androguard inside a Docker container. I&amp;rsquo;ve never used Docker before so it was about time. You can find some general information about the installation process on Arch Linux at this address.
Extensions # Install extensions # &amp;lt;!-- collapse=True --&amp;gt; %install_ext https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dorneanu/ipython/master/extensions/diagmagic.py # Then load extensions %load_ext diagmagic Installed diagmagic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Dynamic Code Analysis - Mastering DroidBox</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/08/05/android-dynamic-code-analysis-mastering-droidbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/08/05/android-dynamic-code-analysis-mastering-droidbox/</guid>
      <description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll have a a closer look at DroidBox which provides a mobile sandbox to look at Android applications. In the previous post I&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with static code analysis. This time will start running our malicious application and look at the &amp;ldquo;noise&amp;rdquo; it generates. That would be:
 file system access network activity interaction with the operating system interaction with other applications etc.  DroidBox is very easy to use and consists of an own system image and kernel meant to log one applications activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disect Android APKs like a Pro - Static code analysis</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/07/07/disect-android-apks-like-a-pro-static-code-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/07/07/disect-android-apks-like-a-pro-static-code-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started writing this IPython notebook in order to make myself more comfortable with Android and its SDK. Due to some personal interests I thought I could also have a look at the available RE tools and learn more about their pros &amp;amp; cos. In particular I had a closer look at AndroGuard which seems to be good at:
 Reverse engineering, Malware and goodware analysis of Android applications &amp;hellip; and more (ninja !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24h Android sniffing using tcpdump</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/23/24h-android-sniffing-using-tcpdump/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/23/24h-android-sniffing-using-tcpdump/</guid>
      <description>For better display results you can also have a look at the 24h Android Monitoring Jupyter Notebook.
 Motivation I&amp;rsquo;ve started this little project since I was mainly interested in the data my smartphone is ending all the time without my knowledge. I have a bunch of apps installed on my phone and I have absolutely no ideea which (kind of) data is beeing transfered to the Internet all day long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>24h Android sniffing using tcpdump - IPython Notebook Version</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/23/24h-android-sniffing-using-tcpdump-ipython-notebook-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/23/24h-android-sniffing-using-tcpdump-ipython-notebook-version/</guid>
      <description>Motivation I&amp;rsquo;ve started this little project since I was mainly interested in the data my smartphone is sending all the time without my knowledge. I have a bunch of apps installed on my phone and I have absolutely no ideea which (kind of) data is beeing transfered to the Internet all day long. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be a great ideea to monitor/sniff my data interface (3G, Edge etc. NOT Wifi) for 24h during my normal daily phone usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert IP ranges to list</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/04/convert-ip-ranges-to-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/04/convert-ip-ranges-to-list/</guid>
      <description>If you got IP ranges in this layout: x.x.x.1-255, y.y.y.42-120 etc., you could easily use this code to generate full IP adresses without any ranges:
ips = &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; x.x.x.1-23 y.y.y.56-12 &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; buf = StringIO.StringIO(ips) while True: line = buf.readline() if line == &amp;#39;&amp;#39;: break else: import re m = re.search(&amp;#39;(.*)\.(.*)\.(.*)\.(.*)&amp;#39;, line) if m: ip_range = m.group(4).split(&amp;#39;-&amp;#39;) if len(ip_range) == 2: ip_addr = range(int(ip_range[0]), int(ip_range[1])+1) for i in ip_addr: print &amp;#34;%s.%s.%s.%s&amp;#34; % (m.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week #13</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/10/18/links-of-the-week-#13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/10/18/links-of-the-week-#13/</guid>
      <description>  CorkaMix: This is indeed insane!
  Why We Hate Infographics (And Why You Should)
    What Happens To Our Body After Drinking Coca Cola?: Coke anybody?
  Kvasir: Network Vulnerability Management System
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Automate nmap scanning</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/09/13/howto-automate-nmap-scanning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/09/13/howto-automate-nmap-scanning/</guid>
      <description>Recently a colleague of mine at nullsecurity.net released a new scanning tool called wnmap. Basically it&amp;rsquo;s a wrapper around nmap which helps automating the scanning process by using simple configuration files. Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at it..
Configuration Make sure you you have downloaded the archive and open src/core/wnmap.conf in order to edit:
 the wnmap path editor preferences global parameters (to use in every scan)  Running the tool Now the obligatory -help message:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank God there is iodine! IPv4 over DNS</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/11/09/thank-god-there-is-iodine-ipv4-over-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/11/09/thank-god-there-is-iodine-ipv4-over-dns/</guid>
      <description>I always knew DNS/ICMP traffic is mostly allowed and un-monitored. It was about time to setup some DNS server on my vServer which would allow me to break free! Thanks God there is iodine which allows you to route IP traffic over DNS.
I was recently at some cafe and thought it would be a great ideea to test my configuration. I&amp;rsquo;ve setup the iodine server a few weeks before.This is what I did:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free PPTP VPN servers</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/06/24/free-pptp-vpn-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/06/24/free-pptp-vpn-servers/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d recommend you all using some VPN to keep your identity safe and private. Here&amp;rsquo;s some setup:
$ pptpsetup --create vpnde --server pptp.freedevpn.com --username free --password --encrypt $ pptpsetup --create vpnca --server freecavpn.com --username free --password --encrypt $ pptpsetup --create vpnl --server freenlvpn.com --username free --password --encrypt $ pptpsetup --create vpnuk --server freeukvpn.com --username free --password --encrypt For the passwords have a look at freenlvpn.com, freedevpn.com, freeukvpn.com, freecavpn.com. The VPN passwords changes every 12 hours, so keep in mind to change whenever the authentication failes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC: Connect to current desktop session using x11vnc and ssh</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/04/04/vnc-connect-to-current-desktop-session-using-x11vnc-and-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/04/04/vnc-connect-to-current-desktop-session-using-x11vnc-and-ssh/</guid>
      <description>x11vnc allows you to connect to real X displays without creating any new X session (fluxbox, twm, gnome etc.). It allows you to control the mouse, keyboard and X events remotely. I usually use it when friends of mine need help and I want to see what exactly they&amp;rsquo;re doing.
Make sure any **ssh server **is running on remote-hostand you have a vnc client installed on your localhost. Also make sure remote-host has x11vnc otherwise this won&amp;rsquo;t make sense at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Block facebook with iptables on OpenWrt</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/04/02/block-facebook-with-iptables-on-openwrt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/04/02/block-facebook-with-iptables-on-openwrt/</guid>
      <description>Say NO to facebook and add these lines to /etc/firewall.user
# This file is interpreted as shell script. # Put your custom $IPT rules here, they will # be executed with each firewall (re-)start. IPT=iptables NET_LAN=192.168.0.0/16 ... # facebook $IPT -I FORWARD -p tcp -m iprange --dst-range 66.220.144.0-66.220.159.255 --dport 443 -j DROP $IPT -I FORWARD -p tcp -m iprange --dst-range 69.63.176.0-69.63.191.255 --dport 443 -j DROP $IPT -I FORWARD -p tcp -m iprange --dst-range 204.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My own cheap NAS &amp;#8211; the OpenWRT way</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/03/19/my-own-cheap-nas-#8211-the-openwrt-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/03/19/my-own-cheap-nas-#8211-the-openwrt-way/</guid>
      <description>Introducing my TP-Link TL-WR1043ND:
Summary  OS: Linux OpenWrt 2.6.32.25 #1 Fri Nov 19 20:27:50 PST 2010 mips GNU/Linux CPU: system type : Atheros AR9132 rev 2 machine : TP-LINK TL-WR1043ND processor : 0 cpu model : MIPS 24Kc V7.4  Filesystems root@OpenWrt:~# df -Ph Filesystem Size Used Available Capacity Mounted on /dev/root 2.1M 2.1M 0 100% /rom tmpfs 14.4M 232.0K 14.2M 2% /tmp tmpfs 512.0K 0 512.0K 0% /dev /dev/sda1 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenBSD 4.8 - First impressions</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/02/04/openbsd-4.8-first-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/02/04/openbsd-4.8-first-impressions/</guid>
      <description>Today I had the big opportunity to setup an OpenBSD based gateway. I&amp;rsquo;ve never used OpenBSD before and I was really excited about. All in one: Really clean (almost spartanic), secure 4.4BSD. Although I had some problems during the partitioning process - I didn&amp;rsquo;t thought they have such a l33t partitioning tool - the installation went smooth. Afterwards I&amp;rsquo;ve fetched the ports and installed some common utilities: No compilation errors etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: SNAT/IP Masquerade between 2 wlan cards on Linux</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/11/25/howto-snat/ip-masquerade-between-2-wlan-cards-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/11/25/howto-snat/ip-masquerade-between-2-wlan-cards-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>Although this is a quite minimalistic howto you should be able to do IP masquerading between your WLAN cards in less than 2 minutes. As I posted here I&amp;rsquo;d like to share use my WLAN cards to share one cards Internet connection with the other one. The following steps don&amp;rsquo;t apply only to wifi cards. The same commands should work on Ethernet cards too. Let&amp;rsquo;s start&amp;hellip;
The Big picture As you see you have 2 networks:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find out your geolocation via MAC address</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/10/07/find-out-your-geolocation-via-mac-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/10/07/find-out-your-geolocation-via-mac-address/</guid>
      <description>Today I found a very interesting article about geoposition localisation based on MAC addresses. MAC addresses ? Yeah, right! As securiteam described here it is possible to find out your location using Google&amp;rsquo;s Location Services REST API. Further information can be found on Dinis Cruz blog. But where is all the data coming from? You may also have noticed Google&amp;rsquo;s Street View cars scanning your neighborhood for WLAN access points. Oh, I have forgotten about that: It wasn&amp;rsquo;t Google&amp;rsquo;s intention as stated here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Secure your server using icmpKNOCK</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/10/03/howto-secure-your-server-using-icmpknock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/10/03/howto-secure-your-server-using-icmpknock/</guid>
      <description>This time I&amp;rsquo;d like to give you a short usage description of icmpKNOCK that was recently released. The main reason I wrote it was lack of security measurements on my boxes. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want any sophisticated IDS tools nor complicated monitoring services. I wanted to implement something which will run on (almost) any platform without any external toolsb. Since the ping utility is available on most modern systems using ICMP packets to communicate with the server was the most reasonable approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>icmpKNOCK v0.2 released</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/09/13/icmpknock-v0.2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/09/13/icmpknock-v0.2-released/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to announce the second main release of icmpKNOCK. I thought it was about time to release a new improved version. I&amp;rsquo;ve mainly focused on the actions mechanism and tried to implement some flexible way of defining actions, adding key pattern and setting payloads. Besides that I have managed it to install a SVN service in order to provide the latest development version of my current projects.
The CHANGELOG for this version isn&amp;rsquo;t quite long.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torrents over TOR?! Don&#39;t!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/05/03/torrents-over-tor-dont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/05/03/torrents-over-tor-dont/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;An increasing number of people are asking us about the recent paper coming out of Inria in France around Bittorrent and privacy attacks. This post tries to explain the attacks and what they imply. There are three pieces to the attack (or three separate attacks that build on each other, if you prefer).&amp;rdquo;
 The first attack is on people who configure their Bittorrent application to proxy their tracker traffic through Tor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Create new Debian domU using Xen on *BSD</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/22/howto-create-new-debian-domu-using-xen-on-bsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/22/howto-create-new-debian-domu-using-xen-on-bsd/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial you&amp;rsquo;ll get detailed information how to setup a fully functionable Debian Lenny system using virtualization software Xen. This entry was written due to high frustration caused by unreliable/outdated articles on the Internet and uncompleted tutorials. This here should be an attempt to describe the installation process completely and provide additional information which might help you solve common problems. The domU system we&amp;rsquo;d like to setup (in our case Debian) provides a neat netboot installer which supports Xen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Qemu networking on NetBSD</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/01/howto-qemu-networking-on-netbsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/01/howto-qemu-networking-on-netbsd/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial I&amp;rsquo;d like to give you some useful examples how to configure network when using Qemu as virtualization machine. The videos in this HowTo were taken on a NetBSD-5_STABLE/amd64 machine using Qemu 0.11.1. **Attention: **On my system I&amp;rsquo;ve used a patched version of Qemu as reported here. However you can use the fd= option to specify an open socket to be used. Example:
$ qemu -cdrom [iso file] -net nic -net tap,fd=3 3&amp;lt;&amp;gt;/dev/tap0 Using this example `tap0″ should be created before the qemu command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetBSD, Linux &amp;#038; Xen - Does it work?</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/11/14/netbsd-linux-#038-xen-does-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/11/14/netbsd-linux-#038-xen-does-it-work/</guid>
      <description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my impressions I made with Xen during the last weeks. I met Xen a few months ago but due to general lack of interest I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the chance to give it a try.Para-virtualization - why bother at all? There were actually no significant reasons why I should use virtualization. But then it started with this thread, followed by this one. The really fascinating - and tough quite useful - aspect of virtualization consists of the hardware access policy which is implemented by the virtualization host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple MAC address generator</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/10/14/simple-mac-address-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/10/14/simple-mac-address-generator/</guid>
      <description>Any time you do some security researches you should better spoof/hide your identity. The best way to do that is to spoof/manipulate the MAC address of your interface. I normally do that when doing WiFi stuff: WEP cracking and such stuff. I usually assign some random MAC address to my interfaces to fully hide my identity.
A MAC address consists of six groups of hexadecimal digits. Each group is separated by hyphens or colons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: SSH-Tunnel over CorkScrew using Tor</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/05/howto-ssh-tunnel-over-corkscrew-using-tor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/05/howto-ssh-tunnel-over-corkscrew-using-tor/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays it seems like we&amp;rsquo;re loosing our privacy and are being taped by video cameras all over. The same applies to Internet surveillance: By daily traffic analysis you can find out who is talking to whom over a public network. This traffic allows others to track your click behaviour and interests. So if any mailicious guy has access to your network traffic (@work, @home …) he will try to find more information about you, like e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>icmpKNOCK - ICMP port knocking server</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/07/31/icmpknock-icmp-port-knocking-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/07/31/icmpknock-icmp-port-knocking-server/</guid>
      <description>Whats this about? If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with port knocking, you should know the basics and how this technique basically works. If don&amp;rsquo;t have a clue what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about, feel free to have a look at the Links section. Most port knocking tools are listening for TCP or UDP packets to arrive on specific ports in a specific order. icmpKNOCK is waiting for ICMP echo requests and checks their payloads. Packets that match given criteria trigger some action, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: RsynCrypto - The backup jewel</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/06/25/howto-rsyncrypto-the-backup-jewel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/06/25/howto-rsyncrypto-the-backup-jewel/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays it is essential to backup your data and keep it safe in case of a data loss event. The most common way to backup (private) data is to use a remote server where you can upload your data. Certainly you want to keep it safe and private So how do you want to guarantee the privacy of the files stored? Upload it to the server and encrypt it afterwards?! Somehow you want to automate this backup process so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to do nothing than running the backup script.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
