<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>xen on blog.dornea.nu</title>
    <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/xen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in xen on blog.dornea.nu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/xen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Create new Debian domU using Xen on *BSD</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/22/howto-create-new-debian-domu-using-xen-on-bsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/22/howto-create-new-debian-domu-using-xen-on-bsd/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial you&amp;rsquo;ll get detailed information how to setup a fully functionable Debian Lenny system using virtualization software Xen. This entry was written due to high frustration caused by unreliable/outdated articles on the Internet and uncompleted tutorials. This here should be an attempt to describe the installation process completely and provide additional information which might help you solve common problems. The domU system we&amp;rsquo;d like to setup (in our case Debian) provides a neat netboot installer which supports Xen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetBSD, Linux &amp;#038; Xen - Does it work?</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/11/14/netbsd-linux-#038-xen-does-it-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/11/14/netbsd-linux-#038-xen-does-it-work/</guid>
      <description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my impressions I made with Xen during the last weeks. I met Xen a few months ago but due to general lack of interest I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the chance to give it a try.Para-virtualization - why bother at all? There were actually no significant reasons why I should use virtualization. But then it started with this thread, followed by this one. The really fascinating - and tough quite useful - aspect of virtualization consists of the hardware access policy which is implemented by the virtualization host.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
