<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>icmpknock on blog.dornea.nu</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/icmpknock/</link><description>Recent content in icmpknock on blog.dornea.nu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/icmpknock/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HowTo: Secure your server using icmpKNOCK</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/10/03/howto-secure-your-server-using-icmpknock/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/10/03/howto-secure-your-server-using-icmpknock/</guid><description>This time I&amp;rsquo;d like to give you a short usage description of icmpKNOCK that was recently released. The main reason I wrote it was lack of security measurements on my boxes. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want any sophisticated IDS tools nor complicated monitoring services. I wanted to implement something which will run on (almost) any platform without any external toolsb. Since the ping utility is available on most modern systems using ICMP packets to communicate with the server was the most reasonable approach.</description></item><item><title>icmpKNOCK v0.2 released</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/09/13/icmpknock-v0.2-released/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/09/13/icmpknock-v0.2-released/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to announce the second main release of icmpKNOCK. I thought it was about time to release a new improved version. I&amp;rsquo;ve mainly focused on the actions mechanism and tried to implement some flexible way of defining actions, adding key pattern and setting payloads. Besides that I have managed it to install a SVN service in order to provide the latest development version of my current projects.
The CHANGELOG for this version isn&amp;rsquo;t quite long.</description></item><item><title>icmpKNOCK - ICMP port knocking server</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/07/31/icmpknock-icmp-port-knocking-server/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/07/31/icmpknock-icmp-port-knocking-server/</guid><description>Whats this about? If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with port knocking, you should know the basics and how this technique basically works. If don&amp;rsquo;t have a clue what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about, feel free to have a look at the Links section. Most port knocking tools are listening for TCP or UDP packets to arrive on specific ports in a specific order. icmpKNOCK is waiting for ICMP echo requests and checks their payloads. Packets that match given criteria trigger some action, e.</description></item></channel></rss>