<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>berlin on blog.dornea.nu</title>
    <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/berlin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in berlin on blog.dornea.nu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/berlin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Digital Future in Berlin</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/05/11/the-digital-future-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/05/11/the-digital-future-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>Like always the obligatory introduction to the event:
 &amp;ldquo;The digital age began 75 years ago in Berlin, when Konrad Zuse created the world’s first functioning computer, the Z3. Since then computers have changed the world, much like the steam engine and the car before them. The biggest changes in connection with digitalisation are still to come.&amp;rdquo; (http://science-match.tagesspiegel.de/the-digital-future)
 Digital Future? Well, that sounded like a whole bunch of topics to be presented at the event: Big Data, communication, data analysis, digital society, future computing, gaming, mobility, networks, optimization, privacy, simulation, security, visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Summit in Berlin 2016</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/04/12/aws-summit-in-berlin-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/04/12/aws-summit-in-berlin-2016/</guid>
      <description>For the first time I&amp;rsquo;ve attended the AWS Summit in Berlin which against my expectations was very interesting. Not having much in common with AWS (at least not yet), from a security perspective the cloud still remains a very neglected threat to companies. As we all know there is some &amp;ldquo;rain&amp;rdquo; coming down from the cloud from time to time. And by &amp;ldquo;rain&amp;rdquo; I mean sensitive data which gets exposed due to misconfigured APIs, weak credentials or insecure applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
