<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>backup on blog.dornea.nu</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/backup/</link><description>Recent content in backup on blog.dornea.nu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Distribute your backups using git-annex</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/06/16/distribute-your-backups-using-git-annex/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/06/16/distribute-your-backups-using-git-annex/</guid><description>Backuping a whole bunch of photos and videos might be a difficult task. Taking care of the consistency of your backups is even more complicated task. Besides that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to have your backups at a single place, thus mitigating the impact of a single point of data loss.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using git-annex for some years but not like a pro user, rather than &amp;ldquo;it just works&amp;rdquo;. Meanwhile I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of ownCloud and I&amp;rsquo;ve liked it because one can access its data via web, mobile client or whatever.</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #17</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/18/links-of-the-week-#17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/18/links-of-the-week-#17/</guid><description> The second operating system hiding in every mobile phone A Portscan by Email - HTTP Over X.509 Revisited BlackBerry and Windows Google BBS Terminal Top 10 Hacker Movies of all time Duplicity + S3: easy, cheap, encrypted, automated full-disk backups for your servers Botnets of the Web: How to hijack one badBIOS: analysis of Weapong grade Malware</description></item><item><title>HowTo: RsynCrypto - The backup jewel</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/06/25/howto-rsyncrypto-the-backup-jewel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/06/25/howto-rsyncrypto-the-backup-jewel/</guid><description>Nowadays it is essential to backup your data and keep it safe in case of a data loss event. The most common way to backup (private) data is to use a remote server where you can upload your data. Certainly you want to keep it safe and private So how do you want to guarantee the privacy of the files stored? Upload it to the server and encrypt it afterwards?! Somehow you want to automate this backup process so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to do nothing than running the backup script.</description></item></channel></rss>