<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>golang on blog.dornea.nu</title>
    <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in golang on blog.dornea.nu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 14:56:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Golang</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/bookmarks/golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 10:28:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/bookmarks/golang/</guid>
      <description>Microservices   Building a global services network using Go, QUIC and Micro
  Microservices on Go with the Go Kit
  How I&amp;rsquo;m writing Serverless services in Golang
 Service discovery allows you to register the location of services, with a user friendly name, so that you can find other services by name. AWS provides a Serverless offering for this, called Cloudmap
 cloud application library
 The most important lesson I hope you take away from this, however, is protecting your business logic from the sea of AWS services and technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A JavaScript keylogger using a websocket Golang server</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/gists/a-javascript-keylogger-using-a-websocket-golang-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 11:12:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/gists/a-javascript-keylogger-using-a-websocket-golang-server/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note taking in 2021</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2021/06/13/note-taking-in-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 14:56:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2021/06/13/note-taking-in-2021/</guid>
      <description>Almost 6 years ago I was blogging about organizing and visualizing knowledge. At that time I was just playing around with Tiddlywiki and using it to collect notes during my CCNA course. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t anticipate to which extent personal knowledge management systems would become famous and trendy. And people nowadays don&amp;rsquo;t blog anymore: They take care of their digital gardens. While most of them seem to be just a collection of random notes, there are actually good ones where you can actually read through the thoughts/notes and learn something new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement an access key rotator</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2021/04/25/implement-an-access-key-rotator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2021/04/25/implement-an-access-key-rotator/</guid>
      <description>Introduction With the recent success of Github actions you can automate lots of things whenever something in your repos changes, e.g. automatically generate static HTML content (using hugo) and push it to some repository for which GitHub Pages has been configured. Check this awesome actions list for more use cases.
Using encrypted secrets defined either per repository or organization, you can bring your Github workflow to the next level: Authenticate against APIs, login to different services while keeping your secrets/credentials away from your repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
