<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>books on blog.dornea.nu</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/books/</link><description>Recent content in books on blog.dornea.nu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Steve Jobs by Walter Isaacson</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/02/01/steve-jobs-by-walter-isaacson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/02/01/steve-jobs-by-walter-isaacson/</guid><description>g
From time to time I like to read about great personalities and how their handling and decisions changed the world. I&amp;rsquo;m not an Apple fan and I do have something against Apple&amp;rsquo;s closed platform approach. I also don&amp;rsquo;t obsessively admire Mr. Jobs and its products, but this book gives you a very good impression how it feeled to work with and for Steve Jobs. Although this is the only book I&amp;rsquo;ve read about him, I think Mr.</description></item><item><title>Android Hacker's Handbook</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/01/15/android-hackers-handbook/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/01/15/android-hackers-handbook/</guid><description>{% img http://dl.dornea.nu/img/2015/18add683b7e400d63d7172be60eb564a.jpg %}
What should I say about this book? A lot has been said and this uppon reasonable grounds. This book is meant to give you an overview of the most important security topics related to Android. Not only you&amp;rsquo;ll get a lot of stuff about Android&amp;rsquo;s internals, you&amp;rsquo;ll also learn about exploits (and how they work) targeting the this platform. I think I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time (and also the full knowledge) to look at any specific detail this book covers.</description></item><item><title>A practical guide to Advanced Networking</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/01/08/a-practical-guide-to-advanced-networking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/01/08/a-practical-guide-to-advanced-networking/</guid><description>During the past months I was from time to time reading all kind of stuff related to networking and security. During this process I came accross this book:
{% img http://dl.dornea.nu/img/2015/3b9c034b88c3d5ea44bd4d6bc4436c0f.jpg %}
I found this book to be very comprehensive and very modern in sense of current topics across the &amp;ldquo;network universe&amp;rdquo;. If you ever wanted to get a more deep insight in how routers communicate with each other or how to setup a VoIP infrastructure, this book is a must.</description></item><item><title>Python for Data Analysis</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/08/06/python-for-data-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/08/06/python-for-data-analysis/</guid><description>I use Python on daily basis. I love IPython and use it as my main shell for every day tasks. So it was a matter of time until I got captivated by panda, scipy and numpy. I&amp;rsquo;ve ordered myself Python for Data Analysis in order to get more familiar with the mentioned libraries. Before that I used to semi-understand how their work and got used to that copy&amp;amp;paste mentality.
This book is not only about data analysis.</description></item></channel></rss>