<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sqlite on blog.dornea.nu</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/sqlite/</link><description>Recent content in sqlite on blog.dornea.nu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/sqlite/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>24h Android sniffing using tcpdump</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/23/24h-android-sniffing-using-tcpdump/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/23/24h-android-sniffing-using-tcpdump/</guid><description>Motivation I&amp;rsquo;ve started this little project since I was mainly interested in the data my smartphone is ending all the time without my knowledge. I have a bunch of apps installed on my phone and I have absolutely no ideea which (kind of) data is beeing transfered to the Internet all day long. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be a great ideea to monitor/sniff my data interface (3G, Edge etc. NOT Wifi) for 24h during my normal daily phone usage.</description></item><item><title>24h Android sniffing using tcpdump - IPython Notebook Version</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/23/24h-android-sniffing-using-tcpdump-ipython-notebook-version/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/23/24h-android-sniffing-using-tcpdump-ipython-notebook-version/</guid><description>Motivation I&amp;rsquo;ve started this little project since I was mainly interested in the data my smartphone is sending all the time without my knowledge. I have a bunch of apps installed on my phone and I have absolutely no ideea which (kind of) data is beeing transfered to the Internet all day long. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d be a great ideea to monitor/sniff my data interface (3G, Edge etc. NOT Wifi) for 24h during my normal daily phone usage.</description></item><item><title>HowTo: Keep your passwords safe using SQLite and SQLCipher</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/07/28/howto-keep-your-passwords-safe-using-sqlite-and-sqlcipher/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/07/28/howto-keep-your-passwords-safe-using-sqlite-and-sqlcipher/</guid><description>I was recently doing some hacks and realized that there must be a way to store gained information in a secure manner. I usually encrypt sensitive information (like passwords, accounts etc.) using GPG. But that&amp;rsquo;s quite unhandy: You always need your private key and the encrypted data is stored unencrypted on the device (unless you&amp;rsquo;re using full disk encryption which shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a problem since data is stored encrypted on the device).</description></item></channel></rss>