<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>openbsd on blog.dornea.nu</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/openbsd/</link><description>Recent content in openbsd on blog.dornea.nu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/openbsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Links of the Week #22</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/20/links-of-the-week-#22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/20/links-of-the-week-#22/</guid><description> Remote Code Execution exploit in WordPress 3.5.1
Dissection of Android malware MouaBad.P
Linux: Keep An Eye On Your System With Glances Monitor
DNA seen through the eyes of a coder
Infection of biological DNA with digital Computer Code
OpenBSD Exploit mitigation techniques
RSA Key Extraction via Low-Bandwidth Acoustic Cryptanalysis</description></item><item><title>Links of the Week #8</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/09/links-of-the-week-#8/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/09/links-of-the-week-#8/</guid><description> Android Bug 82119321: A comprehensive description of the recent Android bug also known as the signature bug FOOAS: Fuck Of As A Service localtunnel: Access your local web server through the internet [A Tour Inside CloudFlare’s Latest Generation Servers}(http://blog.cloudflare.com/a-tour-inside-cloudflares-latest-generation-servers): Really impressive! Here’s What Wi-Fi Would Look Like If We Could See It Why I left OpenBSD: Remember self interview after leaving NetBSD? Function Hooking Part 1 – Hooking shared library function calls in Linux</description></item><item><title>OpenBSD, FreeBSD, NetBSD &amp;#8211; I do love beasts!</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/03/21/openbsd-freebsd-netbsd-#8211-i-do-love-beasts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/03/21/openbsd-freebsd-netbsd-#8211-i-do-love-beasts/</guid><description>&lt;p>It all starts with virtualisation! Since there is no BSD at all on my laptop, I thought I should give the most important ones a chance: FreeBSD, OpenBSD and NetBSD. Although there were several rumours afloat – related to complexity factors (installation, configuration etc.) – I had absolutely no problem setting up *BSD with X11(!!!). Besides that I had a look at the packaging systems provided within each BSD. My conclusion: They are pretty much the same: &lt;strong>make install&lt;/strong> and basta. Here some screenshots:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenBSD 4.8 - First impressions</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/02/04/openbsd-4.8-first-impressions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/02/04/openbsd-4.8-first-impressions/</guid><description>Today I had the big opportunity to setup an OpenBSD based gateway. I&amp;rsquo;ve never used OpenBSD before and I was really excited about. All in one: Really clean (almost spartanic), secure 4.4BSD. Although I had some problems during the partitioning process - I didn&amp;rsquo;t thought they have such a l33t partitioning tool - the installation went smooth. Afterwards I&amp;rsquo;ve fetched the ports and installed some common utilities: No compilation errors etc.</description></item></channel></rss>