<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>x.509 on blog.dornea.nu</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/x.509/</link><description>Recent content in x.509 on blog.dornea.nu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/x.509/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenVPN for paranoids</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/11/17/openvpn-for-paranoids/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/11/17/openvpn-for-paranoids/</guid><description>Continuing my admin series this time I&amp;rsquo;d like to setup a VPN using OpenVPN as user-based VPN solution. Unlike IPSec solutions which require IPSec on both (server and client) sides, securing the VPN tunnel by OpenSSL is a more preferable option.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll try to show which steps have to be taken in order to:
secure the communication channel use up-to-date (and secure!) TLS configurations prevent information leaks when the VPN tunnel is down At least for the last one some additional steps are required to route your traffic only through the VPN tunnel.</description></item><item><title>Manage PKI using OpenSSL</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/10/02/manage-pki-using-openssl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/10/02/manage-pki-using-openssl/</guid><description>In the previous X.509 related post I&amp;rsquo;ve had a look at the internals of a X.509 certficate. This time I want to setup my own PKI using some open source software. This post is a preparation for setting up a VPN using OpenVPN.
Before implementing the PKI let&amp;rsquo;s have a look what a PKI should definitely include (make sure you have a look at the Wikipedia entry):
certificate authority (CA) has a public and a private key used to digitally sign certificates registration authority (RA) verify identify of users requesting information from the CA certificate management system probably the most important component Revision CA types There are several types of CAs:</description></item><item><title>Validating and pinning X.509 certificates</title><link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/05/24/validating-and-pinning-x.509-certificates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/05/24/validating-and-pinning-x.509-certificates/</guid><description>In times of NSA, surveillance and data privacy, protecting your data has become an essential part of your every day life. A good understanding of basic principles is half the battle. In this post I just wanted to have look at SSL/TLS from a developer point of view but also from an users one. On the one hand I wanted to use openssl as a CLI utility to inspect and validate X.</description></item></channel></rss>