<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>misc on blog.dornea.nu</title>
    <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in misc on blog.dornea.nu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.dornea.nu/tags/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 years and 7 days later</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2021/02/08/4-years-and-7-days-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2021/02/08/4-years-and-7-days-later/</guid>
      <description>Hello from the other side If you read this post today you might have noticed there was a huge break since the last post. More than 4 years ago I was actively blogging about security (mostly offensive stuff) and appsec.
So what happened since then? Well not only in private some things have changed but also professionally I kind of switched sides. While being involved in pentests for a while I decided to become more blue-team oriented and help others to build secure products.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Digital Future in Berlin</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/05/11/the-digital-future-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/05/11/the-digital-future-in-berlin/</guid>
      <description>Like always the obligatory introduction to the event:
 &amp;ldquo;The digital age began 75 years ago in Berlin, when Konrad Zuse created the world’s first functioning computer, the Z3. Since then computers have changed the world, much like the steam engine and the car before them. The biggest changes in connection with digitalisation are still to come.&amp;rdquo; (http://science-match.tagesspiegel.de/the-digital-future)
 Digital Future? Well, that sounded like a whole bunch of topics to be presented at the event: Big Data, communication, data analysis, digital society, future computing, gaming, mobility, networks, optimization, privacy, simulation, security, visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye bye VODKA!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/02/01/bye-bye-vodka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2016/02/01/bye-bye-vodka/</guid>
      <description>Nach mehr als 3 Jahren habe ich mich dazu entschloßen, VODKA zu verlassen. Angefangen bei Kabel Deutschland hat mich die Reise im Zuge einer Übernahme zu Vodafone geführt. Der Begriff VODKA selbst (VODafone + KAbel) bedeutete für mich nicht nur das Zusammenführen von zwei Mentalitäten (eigentlich sind es jetzt 3 wenn man Arcor dazu zählt) sondern auch eine gelungene Zusammenarbeit zwischen Rot (Vodafone) und Gelb (Kabel Deutschland). Als AppSec-Spezialist hatte ich das Vergnügen, verschiedene Kabel- als auch Vodafone-Produkte unter die Lupe zu nehmen und mit zur Unternehmssicherheit beizutragen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The iOS 8.1.3 fiasco</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/02/26/the-ios-8.1.3-fiasco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2015/02/26/the-ios-8.1.3-fiasco/</guid>
      <description>From time to time we all seem to ignore the &amp;ldquo;voice of reason&amp;rdquo; and tend to unconsidered actions. This will be a short summary of what could go wrong when one is forced to quick reactions which will result in chaos.
All started with an iPad Air. I have jailbroken the device from the very first touch. That time iOS 7.x was installed and a jailbreak was available for that specific version (iOS 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 - Personal review</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/12/22/2014-personal-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/12/22/2014-personal-review/</guid>
      <description>Well, where should I start? Looking back at my blog archives I&amp;rsquo;ve realized 2014 &amp;ldquo;year of the mobile apps&amp;rdquo; - at least for me. I was heavily involved in analyzing mobile applications: Android and iOS. For the first time in my whole infosec career path I was disassembling iOS applications and doing stuff (binary analysis) I was used to (some years ago). Besides doing a lot of mobile apps analysis, I was pretty much involved in structuring and hacking data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WhatsApp bot</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/06/29/whatsapp-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/06/29/whatsapp-bot/</guid>
      <description>This is what I&amp;rsquo;ve received yesterday from some phone number I don&amp;rsquo;t really know. BTW: Which countrys prefix is that? The crazy thing about it: Every time I was sending a message to it, it responded with:
 Thank you. We have received your message.
 I had a look at the video sent and it seems to belong to some local club here in town. I was receiving some SPAM SMS from them but this time it was sth new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTo: Write pentest reports the easy way</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/05/20/howto-write-pentest-reports-the-easy-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/05/20/howto-write-pentest-reports-the-easy-way/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll try to share an idea I&amp;rsquo;ve had regarding pentest reports. Most of you surely have their own methods and tools to create nice looking reports after have done some pentesting. Since I try to keep things simple I&amp;rsquo;ll give you a rough idea how this could be done without Excel &amp;amp; Co.
Scenario Suppose you conduct a pentest and take notes during it. Afterwards you&amp;rsquo;ll be probably be copy&amp;amp;paste&amp;rsquo;integratedP the whole content into a layout or pre-defined document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unfancy dashboard using matplotlib</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/03/07/unfancy-dashboard-using-matplotlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/03/07/unfancy-dashboard-using-matplotlib/</guid>
      <description>I was recently playing around with D3Â and discovered its dashboard posibilities.dashboarddude.comÂ has a nice compilation of really fancy dashboards (I was mainly interested in D3 but voila&amp;hellip; there are also other ways to do it).
Meanwhile I was remembered of old good IPython Notebook and its plotting features. This is what came out (You can find the code also on Github Gist: https://gist.github.com/dorneanu/9407737):
import datetime as dt import matplotlib.dates as mdates from mpl_toolkits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 24</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/24/links-of-the-week-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/24/links-of-the-week-24/</guid>
      <description>Suterusu Rootkit: Inline Kernel Function Hooking on x86 and ARM
  Oldboot: the first bootkit on Android
  For the Love of Money
    TCP backdoor 32764 or how we could patch the Internet (or part of it ;))   2013 Cyber Attacks Statistics (Summary)
  Decebal: Point-of-Sale Malware - 400 lines of VBScript code from Romania, Researchers warns about evolution of threats and interests to modern retailers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 23</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/17/links-of-the-week-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2014/01/17/links-of-the-week-23/</guid>
      <description>InkTag: Secure Applications on an Untrusted Operating System
  Unicode Security Guide
  Hunting Botnets with ZMap
  EncFS Security Audit
  Hacking Tools Repository
  The Hacker Who Cracked the Code in Iron Man and The Social Network
  Operating System Tutorials
  The Jobless Ph.D. Generation
  The Holy Book of Passwords by Aram Bartholl
  Reconstructing the Cryptanalytic Attack behind the Flame Malware</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 20</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/06/links-of-the-week-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/12/06/links-of-the-week-20/</guid>
      <description> Android Root Detection Techniques Shmoocon 2013 Playlist INSECURE Mag 40 A society of phone Zombies Encrypted peer-to-peer web application platform for decentralized, privacy-preserving applications The UNIX system family tree: Research and BSD Found: Hacker server storing two million pilfered passwords Burp/Zap plugin: generator script  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 15</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/01/links-of-the-week-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/11/01/links-of-the-week-15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://getpocket.com/redirect?url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.exploit-db.com%2Fexploits%2F29290%2F&#34;&gt;Apache / PHP 5.x Remote Code Execution Exploit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.embedded.com/design/safety-and-security/4396040/An-Introduction-to-Elliptic-Curve-Cryptography&#34;&gt;An introduction to elliptic curve cryptography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.cloudflare.com/a-relatively-easy-to-understand-primer-on-elliptic-curve-cryptography&#34;&gt;A (Relatively Easy To Understand) Primer on Elliptic Curve Cryptography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://qandwhat.apps.runkite.com/i-failed-a-twitter-interview/&#34;&gt;I Failed a Twitter Interview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/world/2013/oct/24/former-spy-chief-overheard-acela-twitter&#34;&gt;Former spy chief overheard giving off-the-record interview from Acela train&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 13</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/10/18/links-of-the-week-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/10/18/links-of-the-week-13/</guid>
      <description>  CorkaMix: This is indeed insane!
  Why We Hate Infographics (And Why You Should)
    What Happens To Our Body After Drinking Coca Cola?: Coke anybody?
  Kvasir: Network Vulnerability Management System
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 11</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/09/13/links-of-the-week-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/09/13/links-of-the-week-11/</guid>
      <description> nmap NSE hacking for IT security professionals The Wretched Google Interview Experience Why I left Google I Left Google And Lived To Happily Tell About It The NSA&amp;rsquo;s Cryptographic Capabilities Linux Trojan &amp;ldquo;Hand of Thief&amp;rdquo; ungloved You&amp;rsquo;re Smart. So What? GitHub is Not Your New Resume  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissecting BlackTiny</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/25/dissecting-blacktiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/25/dissecting-blacktiny/</guid>
      <description>To whom it may concern…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 10</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/23/links-of-the-week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/23/links-of-the-week-10/</guid>
      <description> 57 startup lessons Hacking Transcend WiFi SD Cards Hacking the OS X Kernel for Fun and Profiles Here&amp;rsquo;s what you find when you scan the entire Internet in an hour noteZilla: Interactive,clickable, sheet music Linux x86 Program Start Up (How the heck do we get to main()?) Average Income per Programming Language  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo, systemd, consolekit, udev and some failed system update</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/10/gentoo-systemd-consolekit-udev-and-some-failed-system-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/10/gentoo-systemd-consolekit-udev-and-some-failed-system-update/</guid>
      <description>OK, first some explanations:
 systemd is a modern sysvinit &amp;amp; RC replacement for Linux systems. It is supported in Gentoo as an alternate init system. (Source: http://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/Systemd) ConsoleKit is a framework for defining and tracking users, login sessions, and seats. (Source:http://wiki.gentoo.org/wiki/ConsoleKit) udev is the device manager for the Linux kernel. Primarily, it manages device nodes in /devand handles all user space actions when adding/removing devices. Also have a look at eudeva gentoo fork of udev.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 9</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/09/links-of-the-week-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/08/09/links-of-the-week-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weeks links&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://spritesmods.com/?art=hddhack&amp;amp;page=1&#34;&gt;Hard disk hacking:&lt;/a&gt; Learn interesting stuff about hard disks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://securitywatch.pcmag.com/mobile-security/314386-russia-s-massive-android-malware-industry-revealed&#34;&gt;Russia’s Massive Malware Industry Revealed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zdnet.com/bgp-spoofing-routing-router-phishing-why-nothing-on-the-internet-is-actually-secure-7000019015/&#34;&gt;BGP spoofing – why nothing on the internet is actually secure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jaclynkonzelmann.tumblr.com/post/29070457063/why-i-quit-microsoft-to-join-a-5-person-start-up-in&#34;&gt;JACLYN KONZELMANN, Why I Quit Microsoft To Join A 5 Person Start Up In Toronto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oddly-even.com/2013/07/31/the-largest-photo-ever-taken-of-tokyo-is-zoomable-and-it-is-glorious/&#34;&gt;The largest photo ever taken of Tokyo is zoomable, and it is glorious&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ivanristic.com/2013/08/configuring-apache-nginx-and-openssl-for-forward-secrecy.html&#34;&gt;Configuring Apache, Nginx, and OpenSSL for Forward Secrecy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reddit.com/r/netsec/comments/1ju6zh/php_exif_backdoors_generator_using_custom/&#34;&gt;HP EXIF Backdoors generator using custom shellcode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dinge, die ein Informatikerstudent niemals sagen würde</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/26/dinge-die-ein-informatikerstudent-niemals-sagen-w%C3%BCrde/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/26/dinge-die-ein-informatikerstudent-niemals-sagen-w%C3%BCrde/</guid>
      <description>Dinge, die ein informatikstudent niemals sagen würde:
   ich hab sonnenbrand     meine freundin&amp;hellip;     &amp;hellip;lass uns das mit pointern lösen     yey, ein beweis!     ich weiß, warum mein programm funktioniert     ich entwickel erst einmal ein ausführliches konzept und denke an alle mölichen fehlerfälle, bevor ich auch nur eine zeile programmiere     ich hab windows und office legal gekauft     der typ vor mir duftet aber gut     heute kommentiere ich ausführlich     das internet benötige ich nie zum programmieren     wirtschaftsinformatik ist ein völlig gleichwertiger studiengang zu informatik    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 5</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/21/links-of-the-week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/21/links-of-the-week-5/</guid>
      <description>This weeks top links:
 The most sophisticated Android Trojan: Really nice analysis. I think security on mobile devices will become more and more hype. At our current rate of progress, IPv6 will be fully implemented on May 10, 2148: `There is no reason for any individual to have a computer in his home. Well.. Not really! Writing buffer overflow exploits - a tutorial for beginners: Another buffer overflow tutorial. Buffer Overflows - Nopsled and Ret2Libc methods: Just excellent!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 4</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/07/links-of-the-week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/06/07/links-of-the-week-4/</guid>
      <description>How the Prime Meridian Changed the World: Not technical stuff but worth reading.
  OpenSSH keys and the drunken bishop: Ever wondered about that visual fingerprint when generating SSH keys? Well this article brings some light on that. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried on my own and that&amp;rsquo;s fun: $ ssh -o VisualHostKey=yes victor@cia.gov -p 1337 Host key fingerprint is xxxxx +&amp;ndash;[ RSA 2048]&amp;mdash;-+ | .. | | . .. | | o .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of the Week 2</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/05/24/links-of-the-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2013/05/24/links-of-the-week-2/</guid>
      <description>First Glimpse into the Soul of Tamagotchi: Remember my post about 29C3? There I&amp;rsquo;ve first mentioned Natalie and her passion for Tamagotchis. She&amp;rsquo;s doing some progress! Obvisouly! I really like the screenshots. CVE-2013-2094: This is definitely the bug of the week! Have a closer detailed look here. The exploit was ported to x86. Interview with a BlackHat: Part 1, Part 2, Part 3 Your login form posts to HTTPS, but you blew it when you loaded it over HTTP: I can&amp;rsquo;t believe this is still a issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Think before you type part 2</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/02/26/think-before-you-type-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2011/02/26/think-before-you-type-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the type of post where I blame myself for my stupidity (I&amp;rsquo;d call it rather carelessness)What happened? Well all I wanted to do was:
$ dd if=/dev/urandom of=/dev/sda3 Beware of the &amp;ldquo;3&amp;rdquo; at the end. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what really happened but at the end dd was running with:
$ dd if=/dev/urandom of=/dev/sda Damn! I was like: &amp;ldquo;F***! All my data!&amp;rdquo; Fortunately only 4 MBs were &amp;ldquo;randomized&amp;rdquo;. That means: No partition table more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DEADF700? Stuxnet!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/09/27/deadf700-stuxnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/09/27/deadf700-stuxnet/</guid>
      <description>The whole world seems to be concerned about this new worm&amp;hellip; I think it was Stuxnet. Meanwhile a (hex?) pattern is putting the cat among the pigeons. Its about DEADF700. What could this be? The word is that it is the last command Stuxnet is waiting for. The last command before what? Before the whole building explodes? Let&amp;rsquo;s come back to one&amp;rsquo;s senses.
Some translations:
 Text: ÃžÂ­p Binary: 11011110 10101101 11110111 00000000 Base64: 3q33AA== DEC / Char: 222 173 247 0 MD2: 19844451167c6038fde316f1a4fadd7d MD4: 864e882437c8324c06d485b3e505ab8d MD5: 06f14a8de09a925e124034e457ce55a2 SHA1: fac6dd07345c0f7f23ab2cf7506bedcf33e4b451 RIPEMD-160: 08edfc88ccd3c2b0187e03bcf8b72894e8fd7908  Sooooo ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Its time to say goodbye! RIP 2010-07!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/07/29/its-time-to-say-goodbye-rip-2010-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/07/29/its-time-to-say-goodbye-rip-2010-07/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sommersemester 2010 online!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/07/26/sommersemester-2010-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/07/26/sommersemester-2010-online/</guid>
      <description>Ich habe mir die Mühe gemacht, in meinem Studium fÃ¼r ein bisschen Ordnung zu sorgen. Ab sofort sind die Vorlesungsmaterialien sowie die Aufgabenzettel (Lösungen) des letzten Semesters (Sommersemester 2010) online! Solltet ihr geheime Skripte und Aufgabensammlungen bei euch auf der Festplatte aufbewahren, schreibt mir ne Mail. Vielleicht einigen wir uns zu einem Deal und machen das ganze public.
Ich werde versuchen, den Stuff aus dem ersten Semester so schnell wie möglich nachzuliefern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bildungsforschung? Rechtschreibung waere besser</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/05/14/bildungsforschung-rechtschreibung-waere-besser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/05/14/bildungsforschung-rechtschreibung-waere-besser/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Torrents over TOR?! Don&#39;t!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/05/03/torrents-over-tor-dont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/05/03/torrents-over-tor-dont/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;An increasing number of people are asking us about the recent paper coming out of Inria in France around Bittorrent and privacy attacks. This post tries to explain the attacks and what they imply. There are three pieces to the attack (or three separate attacks that build on each other, if you prefer).&amp;rdquo;
 The first attack is on people who configure their Bittorrent application to proxy their tracker traffic through Tor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the mind of a Russian hacker</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/11/inside-the-mind-of-a-russian-hacker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2010/03/11/inside-the-mind-of-a-russian-hacker/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like when you have a maths problem he said. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to find the right tools otherwise you&amp;rsquo;re lost. If you&amp;rsquo;re able to understand the problem, then `use that knowledge in the future.&amp;rdquo;
 This simple comparison applies to hacking, at least to that one that is used to be practiced in Russia. Even Mr. Kaspersky admits that most sophisticated attacks have their origin in his own country. Russian hacking attacks seem to be more professional, the malware design more complicated and technical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep your system up2date!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/09/07/keep-your-system-up2date/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/09/07/keep-your-system-up2date/</guid>
      <description>Due to NetBSD’s great packaging system, software gets updated very frequently. It is very important to have a clean and safe system running and no outdated packages on your system. They might be vulnerable to recently discovered bugs and affect your systems’s security and performance. After updating the package tree (see documentation), I usually update my whole system by running:
$ pkg_chk -su Actually there is nothing wrong about that. Yet there is one big problem, which caused me to seek for another updating mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetBSD, kernel downgrade and some voodoo!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/20/netbsd-kernel-downgrade-and-some-voodoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/20/netbsd-kernel-downgrade-and-some-voodoo/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if you still remember my ACPI suspend/resume problems a few months ago. I once suspended my Linux system to RAM and forgotten to make a proper shutdown. After a while the battery discharged and my laptop was out of power. After some reboots (there were about 15 tries) I finally managed it to boot my system again. Some BIOS error occured every time. That error still keeps my busy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FU here I come!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/12/fu-here-i-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/08/12/fu-here-i-come/</guid>
      <description>Hiermit möchte ich verkünden, dass meine Wahl auf die FU Berlin fiel. Welche Wahl? Na die UNI-Wahl! Nächste Woche gehts dann los mit der Immatrikulation, im Oktober mit dem Studium. Das Vorlesungsverzeichnis schaut schon mal gut aus. Ich freu mich auf jeden Fall!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ganxtaville52 Luebecker Hood</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/07/08/ganxtaville52-luebecker-hood/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/07/08/ganxtaville52-luebecker-hood/</guid>
      <description>Lieber Victor, wir wollen dir eine ganz besondere Ehre zu Teil kommen lassen und dir unseren offiziellen WG-Blog vorstellen:
http://www.ganxtaville52.blogspot.com/
Es ist etwas wirklich wertvolles, also teile diese festgehaltenen Momente auch nur mit Menschen, die dir wirklich nahe stehen und dir etwas bedeuten.
Viel Spaß dabei, um Kommentare, Anregungen usw. wird gebeten.
Beste Grüße, Paul aus der Lübecker Str.
ALSO LEUTE: Geht auf ganxtaville52.blogspot.com!!!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Der Buschfunk kommt</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/05/07/der-buschfunk-kommt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/05/07/der-buschfunk-kommt/</guid>
      <description>Wozu denn die ganze Aufregung über das neue Feature von StudiVZ? Der Name mag ja einen total verwirren, hat aber nichts mit mittelafrikanischer Kommunikationskultur zu tun. Micro-Blogging nennt sich das Ganze und soll zum einen die User darüber informieren, was in ihrer Nähe (gemeint sind ihre Kontakte bei VZ) alles passiert (ist) und zum anderen ihnen die Möglichkeit bieten, ihre Freunde auf dem Laufenden zu Halten.
 &amp;ldquo;Ich bin einkaufen!&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Ich lerne wie ein Weltmeister&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NetBSD rulez!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/05/05/netbsd-rulez/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/05/05/netbsd-rulez/</guid>
      <description>I just started installing NetBSD on my 2nd laptop. Everything works like a charm! (thanks L. for your support xD) I was kind of sick of Linux/Debian and wanted to try something new. I made my decision and installed NetBSD due to its high portability: &amp;ldquo;Of course it runs NetBSD!&amp;rdquo; I heard Thinkpads are very well supported by NetBSD but I need to accomodate to the new system and do some testings before installing it on my main working machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn VIM into your favourite IDE</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/04/24/turn-vim-into-your-favourite-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/04/24/turn-vim-into-your-favourite-ide/</guid>
      <description>Before you start reading this I&amp;rsquo;d recommand you to ask your best friend Google™ for the most common (platform independent) IDEs (Integrated Development Environment). If you want some top 10 of most featured/used/known/whatever IDEs go to Wikipedia and satisfy your needs. So don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong: This article is NOT supposed to give you some comparison nor to influence your oppinion. I&amp;rsquo;ll just satisfy MY needs and give you some kind of reviews in using VIMfor complex projects and daily coding tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why use Python? The n00b mini-review</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/04/07/why-use-python-the-n00b-mini-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/04/07/why-use-python-the-n00b-mini-review/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been coding Python for almost one week. I really thank O&amp;rsquo;Reilly for their good quality and well structured books. If you ever plan to learn Python, just have a look at &amp;ldquo;Learning Python - 3rd Edition&amp;rdquo; by Mark Lutz. You&amp;rsquo;ll love it! And you&amp;rsquo;ll really get impressed and fascinated by Pythons vast functionalities like I did.
So what&amp;rsquo;s the big thing about Python? Well to be honest my answer is simply: Because it&amp;rsquo;s damn cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bye Bye Immobilo!</title>
      <link>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/03/18/bye-bye-immobilo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.dornea.nu/2009/03/18/bye-bye-immobilo/</guid>
      <description>Wow! So schnell kann die Zeit vergehen&amp;hellip;Vor ungefähr 5 Monaten wurde ein gewisser Victor D. in die Büroräume der Firma Golden Immobilien GmbH eingeladen. Grund dafür war ein anstehendes Vorstellungsgespräch. Damals wusste ich noch nicht, welche Herausforderungen mich im Laufe des Praktikums erwarten werden und welch Bereicherung meines Fachwissens noch bevorstand.
Aufgaben Die richtige Bezeichnung meiner Stelle lautete Datenbank-Entwickler. Zu meinen Aufgabenbereichen gehörte überwiegend die Entwicklung neuer (Datenbank)-Funktionen/Funktionalitäten für die Immobilien Suchmaschine immobilo.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
